每当我为世局倍感忧心时
Whenever I get gloomy with the state of the world,
就会想到希思罗机场的入境大厅
I think about the arrivals gate at Heathrow Airport.
世人认为世界充满仇恨与贪婪
General opinion's starting to make out that we live in a world ofhatred and greed,
但我却不苟同
but I don't see that.
在我看来爱似乎无处不在
Seems to me that love is everywhere.
时常并不特别高贵 不值得一提 但是爱永远存在
Often it's not particularly dignified or newsworthy, but it's always there.
父子 母女 夫妻
Fathers and sons, mothers and daughters, husbands and wives,
男朋友 女朋友 老朋友
boyfriends, girlfriends, old friends.
当飞机撞上世贸大楼时
When the planes hit the Twin Towers, as far as I know,
乘客所打出的电话 都不是仇恨或报复
none of the phone calls from the people on board were messages of hate or revenge.
而是爱的信息
They were all messages of love.
如果你仔细找找 你会发现爱其实
If you look for it, I've got a sneaky feeling you'll find that love actually...
无处不在
is all around.
真爱至上
Love Actually
# 我从头到脚 #
# I feel it in my fingers #
# 全身都充满爱 #
# I feel it in my toes #
# I feel it in my toes, yeah #
- # 爱无处不在 # - # 无处不在 #
- # Love is all around me # - # All around me #
- # 因此 # - 你又唱错了 比利
- # And so the... # - I'm afraid you did it again, Bill.
我只是对原版太熟啦
It's just I know the old version so well, you know.
大家都一样
Well, we all do.
- 所以我们才要翻唱老歌呀 - 好吧 再来一次
- That's why we're making the new version. - Right, okay, let's go.
- # 我从头到脚 # - # 从头到脚 #
# I feel it in my fingers # # In my fingers #
# 全身都充满爱 #
# I feel it in my toes #
# I feel it in my toes, yeah #
# 爱无处不在 # 噢 噢
# Love is all... # oh, fuck!
去他的 担担面枝仔冰
Wank, bugger, shitting, arsehead and hole!
再来一次
Start again.
- # 我从头到脚 # - # 从头到脚 #
- # I feel it in my fingers # - # ln my fingers #
# 全身都充满爱 #
# I feel it in my toes #
# I feel it in my toes, yeah #
# 圣诞节无处不在 #
# Christmas is all around me #
- # 无处不在 # - # 幸福洋溢在心头 #
- # All around me # - # And so the feeling grows #
# 幸福洋溢在心头 #
# So my feeling grows #
- # 欢乐气氛四处飘 # - # 四处飘 #
- # It's written in the wind # - # ln the wind #
# 我去哪里都能看到 #
# It's everywhere I go #
# 都能看到 #
# Everywhere I go #
- # 如果你爱圣诞节 # - # 爱圣诞节 #
- # So if you really love Christmas # - # Love Christmas #
# 祈祷天公下大雪 #
# Come on and let it snow #
- # 祈祷天公下大雪 # - 这歌词烂透了 是不是？
- # Come on and let it snow # - This is shit, isn't it?
是呀 一定会卖翻天
Yep, solid gold shit, maestro.
圣诞节前五周
- 天 我迟到了 - 就在街角
- God, I'm so late. - It's just round the corner. You'll make it.
你真的不介意我一样人去吗？
Are you sure... you don't mind me going without you?
不会啦 我全身病奄奄的
No, really. I'm just feeling so rotten.
- 我爱你 - 我知道
- I love you. - I know.
你病到丑不啦叽我也爱你
I love you even when you're sick and look disgusting.
我知道啦 快去吧 千万别错过了
I know. Now go, or you will actually miss it.
好
Right.
- 我说过我爱你吗？- 有啦
- Did I mention that I love you? - Yes, you did.
你真没用
Get out, loser.
凯伦 又是我
Karen, it's me again.
抱歉 我找不到 另外一样能说话的人
I'm sorry, I... I literally don't have anybody else to talk to.
没问题 只是我不方便 我再给你打回去吧？
Absolutely. Horrible moment right now, though. Can I call you back?
- 好 - 我并不是不体谅你刚死了老婆
- Of course. - Doesn't mean I'm not terribly concerned that your wife just died.
我明白
Understood.
去忙吧 待会再聊
Uh, bugger off and call me later.
- 有什么大新闻？- 我们分到圣诞剧角色了
- So what's this big news, then? - We've been given our parts in the nativity play.
我要演龙虾耶
And I'm the lobster.
- 龙虾？- 对呀
- The lobster? - Yeah.
- 圣诞剧？- 对
- In the nativity play? - Yeah.
- 第一支龙虾 - 耶稣诞生时有不少龙虾在场？
- First lobster. - There was more than one lobster present at the birth of Jesus?
真的？
Duh.
英国最可口的三明治
Best sandwiches in Britain.
尝尝我的坚果
Try my lovely nuts?
美女要吃美式松糕
Beautiful muffin for a beautiful lady.
早安 我未来的老婆
Morning, my future wife.
你们可以停了 谢谢
Okay, you can stop there? Thanks.
再给我一点橙色的滤光板
Dave, I'm gonna need a couple of orange gels please, mate.
对了 刚才他说我叫约翰 但大家都叫我杰克
By the way, he introduced me as John, but actually everyone calls me Jack.
好的 很高兴认识你 杰克
Oh, fine. Nice to meet you, Jack.
- 他没把我介绍错 我什么时候都叫茱蒂 - 茱蒂很好啊
- He got me right, though. I'm justJudy. - Oh, great, JustJudy.
- 这次不搞鬼？- 不搞鬼
- No surprises? - No surprises.
- 别像单身派对那样？- 保证不会
- Not like the stag night? - Unlike the stag night.
- 你承认找妓女是个错误 - 是的
- Do you admit the Brazilian prostitutes were a mistake? - I do.
如果他们不是人妖就好了
And it would have been much better if they'd not turned out to be men?
那倒是
That is true.
祝好运
Good luck, kiddo.
Prime Minister, over here!
谢谢
Thank you.
欢迎 首相大人 我要练习挥手
Welcome, Prime Minister. I must work on my wave.
你好
How are you?
你感觉如何？酷毙了 好有权力
How are you feeling? Um, cool, powerful.
你想见见首相府员工吗
Would you like to meet your household staff?
好的 我很乐意
Yes, I would like that very much indeed.
只要不马上治理国家就行
Anything to put off actually running the country.
- 这位是泰伦 他是总管 - 早安 先生
- This is Terence. - He's in charge.
早 我有个叔叔也叫泰伦
Good morning, sir. Good morning. I had an uncle called Terence once. Hated him.
我超讨厌他 变态佬一样 不过我喜欢你
I think he was a pervert. But I very much like the look of you.
- 这是派蒂 - 你好 派蒂
- This is Pat. - Hello, Pat.
早安 我是管家
Good morning, sir. I'm the housekeeper.
好 我会比上一任好很多
Oh, right. Well, should be a lot easier with me than with the last lot.
没有吵闹的小孩和吓人的老婆
No nappies, no teenagers, no scary wife.
这是娜塔莉 她跟你一样是新来的
And this is Natalie. She's new, like you.
- 你好 娜塔莉 - 你好 大卫
- Hello, Natalie. - Hello, David.
我是说首相大人 靠 我竟然叫你的名字
I mean, sir. Shit, I can't believe I've just said that.
我说"靠"了 两次 真是对不起 先生
And now I've gone and said "shit." Twice. I'm so sorry, sir.
没关系! 如果你说"干" 那就麻烦了
It's fine, it's fine. You could have said "fuck" and then we'd have been in real trouble.
我有预感第一天就会"干"错事
Thank you, sir. I did have an awful premonition I was gonna fuck up on my first day.
讨厌!
Oh, piss it.
好 我这就去拿我的东西 好来着手治理国事
Right. I'll go get my things. And then let's fix the country, shall we?
是呀 这样最好
Yeah, I can't see why not.
- 没关系 - 我简直是语无伦次
- It's all right. - Did you see what I did? Yes, I did. Just went blah.
- 喂 - 我在这儿
- Hello - there.
我在这儿 谢谢
Yes, and I'm in here. Okay, good. Thank you.
啊惨了
Oh, no.
这真是不方便
That is so inconvenient.
在上帝面前
In the presence of God,
彼得和茱丽叶相互同意
Peter and Juliet have given their consent...
并向对方立下誓约
and made their marriage vows to each other.
他们藉由交换婚戒互订终生
They have declared their marriage by the giving and receiving of rings.
我在此宣布他们结为夫妻
I therefore proclaim that they are husband and wife.
- 你这次没给我搞鬼 - 是呀 我成熟了
- And you resisted the temptation for surprises? - Yeah, I'm mature now.
# Love, love, love #
- 这是你安排的?
- # Love, love, love # - Did you do this?
不是
Uh, no.
# Love, love, love, love #
# There's nothing you can do that can't be done #
噢 这
oh, it's...
# There's nothing you can sing that can't be sung #
# There's nothing you can say but you can learn how to play the game #
# It's easy #
# All you need is love #
# All you need is love, love #
# Love is all you need #
喂 你在这儿干嘛
Hello. What the hell are you doing here?
我只是来借几张CD
Oh, I just, uh, popped over to borrow some old CDs.
- 女主人让你进来的？- 对
- The lady of the house let you in, did she? - Uh, yeah.
- 她还真好心 - 是的
- Lovely, obliging girl. - Yeah.
我提早回来看她好点没有 这张不错
I just thought I'd pop back before the reception, see if she's better. This is good.
- 噢 - 我在想
- Oh. - Listen, um, I've been thinking.
我想礼拜五妈生日请她吃个饭
I think perhaps we ought to take Mum out for her birthday on Friday.
今年我们没怎么陪她
What do you think? I just feel we've been bad sons this year. Okay.
好 只是有点老套
Sounds fine. A bit, you know, boring, but fine.
快来啦 大傢伙! 我脱光了哦 趁詹米没回来我要干两次
Hurry up, big boy. I'm naked and I want you at least twice beforeJamie gets home.
真高兴见到大家
I am so happy to see you guys.
- 来点可口点心？- 不 谢了
- Delicious delicacy? - Uh, no, thanks.
美味佳肴?
Taste explosion?
- 想吃吗？- 不 谢了
- Food? - No, thanks.
卖相很差 对吧
Yeah, a bit dodgy, isn't it?
活像死婴儿手指头
Looks like a dead baby's finger. Eew.
味道也一样差
Oh, yeah, tastes like it too.
- 我是柯林 - 我是南茜
- I'm Colin, by the way. I'm Nancy.
- 好 你做哪一行？- 我是个厨师 - 你也做婚宴外烩吗?
- Wicked. And what do you do, Nancy? - I'm a cook. - Ever do weddings?
- 没错 我做 - 他们应该找你才对 - 他们找过我
- Yes, I do. - They should have asked you to do this one. - They did.
- 真希望你没有拒绝 - 我没有
- God, I wish you hadn't have turned it down. - I didn't.
是喔
Right.
- 我知道我为什么找不到真爱 - 为什么
- I have just worked out why I can never find true love. - Why's that?
英国女人都太臭美了
English girls. They're stuck up, you see.
酷而有幽默感的女生比较喜欢我
And I am primarily attractive to girls who are, you know, cooler, game for a laugh.
就像美国美眉 所以我应该去美国!
Like American girls. So I should just go to America.
随便都能把到马子 对吧
I would get a girlfriend there instantly. What do you think?
屁啦 柯林
I think it's crap, Colin.
你错了 美国美眉最爱听英国口音
No, that's where you're wrong. American girls would seriously dig me with my cute British accent.
- 你才没英国口音 - 我有
- You don't have a cute British accent. - Yes, I do!
我要去美国
I'm going to America.
你是个寂寞难耐的丑男 接受事实吧
Colin. You're a lonely, ugly arsehole and you must accept it.
才不 我是性感之神 我只是生错地方了
Never. I am Colin, God of Sex. I'm just on the wrong continent, that's all.
请安静一下 灯光马上就要打好了
A bit of quiet while we finish the lighting, guys.
今天的交通简直…
I tell you, I thought I was never gonna make it here today.
难以置信
The traffic was just... oh, unbelievable.
茱蒂 你这次能不能把你的上衣脱了？
Judy, um, could you take the top off this time?
我们必须知道怎么打灯光才能照到你的乳头
Lighting and camera need to know when we're actually gonna see the, um, nipples and when we're not.
好的 没问题
Yes, okay. Right.
至少这里很暖和 不总是这么暖和的
Well, at least it's nice and warm in here. It's not always the case, is it?
我有次为布拉德·彼特在《火线大逃亡》里做替身…
I was standing in for Brad Pitt once on, you know, Seven Years In Tibet.
- 哦 是的 - 他妈的冷死了
- Yes, yeah. - Bloody freezing, right...
伙计们 时间紧凑 我们得加快速度了
Yeah, sorry, guys. Time's pretty tight and we have to get the actors in.
- 好吧 - 我保证不看
- Fine. - I promise I won't look.
好 让我们再来一次
Right, let's have another look at that then, please. Okay.
你可不可以把手放在她胸部上?
And Jerry says if you could just put your hands on her breasts.
- 好的 我可以放吗？- 可以
- Oh, right, okay, yeah. Is that all right? - Yes. Yeah, fine.
我先把手弄暖和点
I'll warm 'em up.
请搓揉一下它们
Right. And massage them, please.
好的
Right.
13号路口今早真让人抓狂 不是吗
It's Junction 13 that's just murder, isn't it? Oh, yeah.
车堵得滴水不通
Total gridlock this morning.
我跟琼有充裕时间筹备葬礼
Jo and I had a lot of time to prepare for this moment.
她的一些要求
Some of her, uh, requests, uh, for instance,
比如说 她要求我 带名模克劳蒂参加葬礼
that I should bring Claudia Schiffer as my date to the funeral...
不过她知道我不会理她
I was confident she expected me to ignore.
但是有些要求她却坚持到底
But others she was pretty damn clear about.
她第一次提到这件事
When she first mentioned what's about to happen,
我就说 "除非我死了"
I said, "over my dead body."
她说 "不 丹尼尔 死的是我"
And she said, "No, Daniel, over mine."
我亲爱的妻子
And, uh, as usual, my darling girl...
山姆的妈妈 还是说对了
and Sam's darling mum, was right.
她不是透过我向大家告别
So she's going to say her final farewell to you, not through me,
而是不可避免的
but inevitably...
很酷地
ever so coolly...
透过七十年代男孩团体的歌
through the immortal genius of the Bay City Rollers.
# Bye-bye, baby Baby, good-bye #
# Bye, baby Baby, bye-bye #
# Bye-bye, baby Don't make me cry #
# You're the one girl in town I'd marry #
# Girl, I'd marry you now if I were free #
# I wish it could be #
# I could love you but why begin it #
# 'Cause there ain't any future in it #
# She's got me but I'm not free #
# So, bye-bye, baby Baby, good-bye #
# Bye, baby Baby, bye-bye #
# Bye-bye, baby Don't make me cry #
你爱他吗?
Do you love him?
什么？
Uh, what?
我只想问问 也许你很想跟谁聊聊
No, I just thought I'd ask the blunt question in case it was the right one and you needed someone to talk to about it.
你想吐露心声却没人敢问 你可能真的想吐露心声
And no one had ever asked you, so you'd never been able to talk about it even though you might have wanted to.
不 绝对不是
No, no. No is the answer. Absolutely not.
所以你并不爱他 是的
So, that's a no then? Yes.
嗯
Um...
这个DJ 你觉得怎么样？世上最烂的DJ？
This D.J., what do you reckon? The worst in history?
大概吧 要看他下一首放什么歌
Probably. I think it all hangs on the next song.
这歌是献给有情人的
Now here's one for the lovers.
现场一定有很多对热恋情侣
That's quite a few of you. I shouldn't be surprised and a half.
# And they called it puppy love #
- 答案揭晓了 - 世上最烂的DJ
- He's done it. It's official. - Worst D.J. In the world.
# Oh, I guess they'll never know #
莎拉在等你
Sarah is waiting for you.
对 好
Oh, yes, of course. Um...
很好
Great. Uh, good, good.
蜜雅 你好吗？工作还习惯吗？
How are you doing, Mia? Are you settling in fine, learning who to avoid?
很习惯
Absolutely.
哈利 莎拉 关掉手机
Harry? Sarah, switch off your phone...
告诉我你在这儿做了多久
and, um, tell me exactly how long it is that you've been working here.
嗯
Um...
两年零七个月
Two years, seven months,
三天又两小时？
three days and, I suppose, what, two hours?
你爱上卡尔公司神秘的设计师有多久
And how long have you been in love with karl, our enigmatic chief designer?
嗯
Um...
两年七个月三天 一个小时又三十分钟
Two years, seven months, three days and, I suppose, an hour and 30 minutes.
我就知道 大家都知道吗?
Thought as much. Do you think everybody knows?
- 知道 - 卡尔知道吗？- 知道
- Yes. - Do you think karl knows? - Yes.
这真是坏消息
Oh, that is... that is bad news.
我只觉得你该采取行动了
Well, I just thought that maybe the time had come to do something about it.
- 什么行动？- 先邀他喝酒
- Like what? - Invite him out for a drink, and then after about 20 minutes,
跟他说你想跟他结婚生宝宝
casually drop into the conversation the fact that you'd like to marry him and have lots of sex and babies.
- 你知道我想？- 对
- You know that? - Yes.
卡尔也知道
And so does karl.
为了大家考虑一下
Think about it, for all our sakes.
圣诞节快到了
It's Christmas.
好的 我会的
Certainly. Excellent.
谢了 老板
Will do. Thanks, boss.
- 嗨 莎拉 - 嗨 卡尔
- Hi, Sarah. - Hi, karl.
打扰
Excuse me.
# Come on and let it show #
宝贝
Babe.
没问题 说吧
Absolutely. Fire away.
蜜雅 关小声点好吗
Mia? Mia, could you turn that down?
怎么了
What is that?
这是摇滚传奇麦比利的圣诞歌
And that was the Christmas effort by the once-great Billy Mack.
啊亲爱的 他早就过气了
Oh, dear me, how are the mighty fallen.
我敢拍胸脯打包票 这是本世纪最烂的曲
I could safely put my hand up my arse and say that is the worst record I've heard this century.
不过巧的是 比利呢
Oh, and coincidentally, I believe Billy will be...
是本台另一位DJ的来宾
a guest on my friend Mike's show in a few minutes'time.
欢迎你 比利
Welcome back, Bill.
欢迎你接受访问
So, Billy, welcome back to the airwaves.
你翻唱了"爱无处不在"
New Christmas single, cover of"Love Is All Around."
我们把爱改成圣诞节
Except we've changed the word "love" to "Christmas."
是的 圣诞节对你很重要吗
Yes. Uh, is that an important message to you, Bill?
并不是 麦克
Not really, Mike.
圣诞节要跟你爱的人一起过
Christmas is a time for people with someone they love in their lives.
- 你没有吗？- 我没有
- And that's not you? - That's not me, Michael.
我成名太早 贪图享乐
When I was young and successful, I was greedy and foolish.
现在只能孤老度过余生
And now I'm left with no one, wrinkled and alone.
多谢了
Wow. Um, thanks for that, Bill.
- 谢什么？- 谢谢你说老实话
- For what? - Well, for actually giving a real answer to a question.
偶像歌手很少说实话
Doesn't often happen here at Radio Watford, I can tell you.
- 你问什么我都老实回答 - 你最棒的炒饭对象？
- Ask me anything you like, I'll tell you the truth. - Uh, best shag you ever had?
- 小甜甜布兰妮 - 哇
- Britney Spears. - Wow.
开玩笑的啦 她逊毙了
No, only kidding. She was rubbish.
我再问你
Okay. Um, here's one. How do you think...
你的新歌比得上经典老歌吗
the new record compares to your old classic stuff?
拜托 你也知道这首歌逊爆了
Oh, come on, Mikey. You know as well as I do the record's crap.
我只希望 今年圣诞节冠军单曲得主 不是七年级偶像歌手
But wouldn't it be great if number one this Christmas wasn't some smug teenager,
而是一个想咸鱼翻身的老歌星
but an old ex-heroin addict searching for a comeback at any price?
那些男孩团体到了圣诞节
All those young popsters, come Christmas Day,
全都会把到漂亮美眉
they'll be stretched out naked with a cute bird balancing on their balls.
我却得跟经纪人老乔窝在家里
And I'll be stuck in some dingy flat with me manager, Joe,
全世界最丑的男人
ugliest man in the world.
唱片卖不好 哪儿都不能去
Fucking miserable because our fucking gamble didn't pay off.
小朋友 如果你跟欧巴桑一样 相信世上有圣诞老公公
So if you believe in Father Christmas, children, like your Uncle Billy does,
就去买我的烂单曲
buy my festering turd of a record.
听听我们是怎么硬拗的
And particularly enjoy the incredible crassness of the moment...
在第四句歌词多塞了一个音节
when we try to squeeze an extra syllable into the fourth line.
我猜你说的是 # 如果你爱圣诞节 #
I think you're referring to... # lf you really love Christmas #
祈祷天公下大雪
"Come on and let it snow." ouch!
我再播放一次
So, uh, here it is one more time.
今年应景的圣诞单曲
The dark horse for this year's Christmas number one,
"圣诞节无处不在"
"Christmas Is All Around."
谢谢你 接下来是整点新闻
Thank you, Billy. After this, the news.
首相已经有麻烦了吗
Is the new Prime Minister in trouble already?
# I feel it in my fingers #
(圣诞节前四周) - 接下来是什么？- 美国总统的来访
- okay, what's next? - The president's visit. Ah, yes, yes.
这件事很棘手
I fear this is going to be a difficult one to play.
党内同志强烈认为
Alex? There's a very strong feeling in the party...
不能像上任首相那样 被牵着鼻子走
we mustn't allow ourselves to be bullied from pillar to post like the last government.
这是首次重大的考验 态度必须强硬
Hear. Hear. This is our first really important test. Let's take a stand. Right.
没错 我了解 但是我决定
Right. I understand that, but I have decided... not to.
这次不要
Not this time. We will, of course, try to be clever,
我们不要忘记 美国是全球最强大的国家
but let's not forget that America is the most powerful country in the world.
我不要像个任性的小孩
I'm not gonna act like a petulant child.
我要跟谁上床才吃得到茶点？
Who do you have to screw round here to get a cup of tea and a chocolate biscuit?
是喔
Right.
请进
Yeah, come in.
这是财政部的文件
These have just come through from the Treasury.
- 嗯 嗯 - 这是给你的
- Uh-huh. - And these are for you.
- 太好了 谢谢 - 我就希望你会胜选
- Excellent. Thanks a lot. - I was hoping you'd win.
我也会对另一个傢伙不错 只是我不会给他巧克力饼干
Not that I wouldn't have been nice to the other bloke too. Just always given him the boring biscuits with no chocolate.
多谢了
Thanks very much.
娜塔莉
Thanks, Natalie.
天啊振作点 拜托 你是首相
Oh God. Come on. Get a grip. You're the prime minister, for God's sake.
你觉得我们的新首相怎么样?
Raise the lamp a bit.
哦 我挺喜欢他的
So, what do you reckon to our new prime minister, then? Oh, I like him.
只是想不通他为什么不结婚
I can't understand why he's not married, though. Well, you know the type.
他应该是个工作狂 工作就是他的妻子
He's, uh, married to his job.
要不然他就是个同性恋
Either that or gay as a picnic basket.
打扰一下
Um, excuse me.
茱蒂 你的乳头可不可以低一点 然后稍微向左倾斜
Judy, if you could just lower the nipples and cheat them a bit to the left.
好的
Okay.
茱蒂 我必须说 这是一种享受
You know, I have to say, Judy, this is a real pleasure.
能找到一样可以谈心的人真是个享受
It's lovely to find someone I can actually chat to.
- 谢谢你 - 不谢
- Thank you. - Uh, well, you know.
- 我也有同感 - 谢谢你
- And ditto. - Thank you.
- 茱蒂 请继续下去 - 哦
- And the move again, please, Judy. - Oh.
- 哦 对不起 - 对不起 你没事吧
- Oh, God, I'm sorry. - Are you all right? Yeah, fine.
- 好消息 - 什么
- Exciting news. - What?
我买了去美国的机票
I've bought a ticket to the States.
- 三礼拜后出发 - 不是吧
- I'm off in three weeks. - No!
- 是啊! 我要去威斯康辛州 这个好地方 - 不
- Yes! To a fantastic place called Wisconsin. - No!
威斯康辛辣妹 我来也!
Yes! Wisconsin babes.
- 哈哈 我来了 - 不
- Here comes Sir Colin! - No, Col.
美国是有很多辣妹
There are a few babes in America, I grant you,
不过她们只跟有钱帅哥交往
but they're already going out with rich, attractive guys.
东尼 你是在嫉妒我
Now, Tone, you're just jealous.
你明知道美国每一家酒吧
You know perfectly well that any bar anywhere in America...
至少都有十个辣妹
contains ten girls more beautiful...
会想要跟我嘿咻 全英国都没这么多
and more likely to have sex with me than the whole of the United kingdom.
屁啦 你疯了
That is total bollocks.
- 你是真的疯了 - 没有 她们会把我当成
- You've actually gone mad now. No, I'm wise.
没有奇怪家庭的威廉王子
Stateside, I am Prince William without the weird family.
- 才不会咧 - 才会
- No, Colin, - no! Yes!
不
Nyet! Da!
亲爱的
Nein! Ja, darling.
我并不喜欢办圣诞派对
Right, the Christmas party. Not my favorite night of the year...
所以交给你去安排吧
and your unhappy job to organize.
- 说吧 - 很简单
- Tell me. - Well, it's basic, really.
先找到场地 多买几瓶酒 多准备一些吃的
Find a venue, over order on the drinks, bulk buy the guacamole...
警告女生别接近凯文的咸猪手
and advise the girls to avoid kevin if they want their breasts un-fondled.
- 太太和家人也要邀请吗 - 对 不过不要小孩
- Wives and family and stuff? - Yes. I mean, not children,
只请太太跟女友之类的
but their wives and girlfriends, et cetera.
你不会带
Oh, Christ, you haven't got some horrible six-foot, tight-T-shirt-wearing
打扮劲爆的男友吧
boyfriend you'll be bringing, have you?
不会 我只会在树枝下等着被吻
No, I'll just be hanging around the mistletoe... hoping to be kissed.
真的吗?
Really?
真的
Right.
他整天都躲在房间 现在一定也在
He now spends all the time in his room.
那没什么 我家那小鬼
I mean, he'll be up there now. There's nothing unusual about that.
小柏?
My horrid son... Bernard?
他也成天躲在房间里 谢天谢地
Bernard stays in his room all the time. Thank goodness.
可是凯伦 他是寸步不离房间
Yeah, but, Karen, this is all the time.
我很怕他有问题
I'm afraid that there's something really wrong, you know?
这跟他妈的死有关
I mean, clearly it's about his mum, but Christ, he...
搞不好他在往眼球注射海洛因
he might be injecting heroin into his eyeballs for all I know.
- 十一岁就吸毒？- 也许不是眼球
- At the age of 11? - Well, maybe not his eyeballs, then.
是血管好吧
Maybejust his veins.
问题是都是他妈妈跟他谈心
You see, the problem is, it was his mum who always used to talk to him, you know and...
我不晓得 当继父这档事
I don't know, the whole stepfather thing...
突然变得很重要
seems suddenly to somehow matter like it never did before.
遇到这种事谁都会很难过
Listen, it was always going to be a totally shit time.
你要有耐心
Just be patient.
检查他房间有没有针头
And maybe check the room for needles.
他偶尔会出来
And then when he sometimes does come out,
看起来显然哭过
it's obvious he's been crying.
她死得太早了
It's just such a ridiculous waste.
现在山姆又这样
And then if it's going to ruin Sam's life as well...
我不知道如何是好
I just don't know.
振作点
Get a grip.
没有人喜欢爱哭鬼 你哭个不停没人会跟你上床的
People hate sissies. No one's ever gonna shag you if you cry all the time.
是呀 没错
Yeah, absolutely.
好建议
Helpful.
那
So,
怎么了？山姆
what's the problem, Samuel?
是因为妈妈
Is it just Mum,
还是别的事
or is it something else, huh?
是学校吗
Maybe... school?
你被同学欺负了？
Are you being bullied?
还是更严重的事
Or is it something worse?
你能给我点暗示吗
Can you give me any clues at all?
- 你真的想知道？- 我真的想知道
- You really want to know? - I really want to know.
就算你帮不上忙也想知道?
Even though you won't be able to do anything to help?
就算是这样
Even if that's the case, yeah.
是的
Okay. Well,
老实说 实际上
the truth is,
我爱上了一个人
actually, I'm in love.
什么
Sorry?
我应该为妈难过 我也难过 可是我爱上了一个人
I know I should be thinking about Mum all the time, and I am,
那是她死前的事 我也没办法
but the truth is I'm in love, and I was before she died, and there's nothing I can do about it.
你还太小了吧
Aren't you a bit young to be in love?
不小
No.
好 嗯
Oh, well, okay, right.
我真的松了一口气
Well, I mean, I'm a little relieved.
为什么
Why?
因为我 我以为是更惨的事
Well, because I thought it would be something worse.
有比受爱情煎熬更惨的事吗?
Worse than the total agony of being in love?
嗯…
Um...
没有 你说得对
No, you're right.
谈恋爱很痛苦
Yeah, total agony.
- 晚安 莎拉 - 晚安 卡尔
- Night, Sarah. - Night, karl.
是的 当然
Yeah? Absolutely.
我有空 说吧
Free as a bird. Fire away.
我又孤单一人了
Alone again.
很自然
Naturally.
我明天一早再处理
I'll deal with it in the morning. Right.
- 娜塔莉 - 先生
- Ah, Natalie. - Sir.
谢谢 娜塔莉
Thanks. Natalie.
我开始觉得
Um, I'm starting to feel...
每天都见到你有点别扭
uncomfortable about us working in such close proximity every day...
因为我对你一无所知
and me knowing so little about you.
这是不对的
It seems, uh... It seems elitist and wrong.
我没什么特别的
Well, there's not much to know.
你住在哪儿呢
Well, um, where do you live, for instance?
旺斯沃斯 比较穷那一区
Wandsworth. The dodgy end.
我老妹也住在旺斯沃斯
Ah, my sister lives in Wandsworth.
哦
Oh. Yeah.
比较穷的那一区在哪儿?
So which exactly is the "dodgy end"?
就在商业街尽头 哈利街 靠近皇后头酒吧
Right at the end of the high street. Harris Street. Near the Queen's Head.
是呀 那儿是比较穷
Oh, yeah, yeah, that is dodgy.
你跟老公或男友一起住吗
Um, and, uh, you live with your husband... uh, boyfriend...
有三个可爱的私生子？
three illegitimate but charming children?
没有啦 刚跟男友分手 回去跟爸妈住一阵子
No, I've, um, just split up with my boyfriend actually, so I'm back with my mum and dad for a while.
- 很遗憾 - 不 没什么 跟他分手也好
- Ah. Sorry. - No, it's fine. I'm well shot of him.
- 他说我太胖了 - 你说什么
- He said I was getting fat. - I beg your pardon?
他说没人喜欢有象腿的女人
He said no one's gonna fancy a girl with thighs the size ofbig tree trunks.
他并不是一个好人
Not a nice guy, actually, in the end.
啊
Ah.
你知道
You know, um,
身为首相我可以叫人刺杀他
being prime minister, I could just have him murdered.
谢谢你 我会考虑的
Thank you, sir. I'll think about it.
特勤组非常厉害
Do. The S.A.S. Are absolutely charming.
打一通电话就有冷血杀手
Ruthless trained killers are just a phone call away.
啊天啊
Oh, God.
你也有这种问题吗
You have this kind of problem?
当然有了 骚娘子
Yeah, course you did, you saucy minx.
来吧 我们想个办法解决
So, let's go.
我也当过小孩呀
We can definitely crack this. Remember, I was a kid once too.
对方是同学 对吧?
So come on. It's someone at school. Right?
- 对 - 很好 她或他 喜欢你吗
- Yeah. - Uh-huh, good, good. And what does she... he... feel about you?
她根本不认识我
She doesn't even know my name.
就算认识也会讨厌我的
And even if she did, she'd despise me.
她是学校最酷的女生 她好漂亮 大家都崇拜她
She's the coolest girl in school, and everyone worships her because she's heaven.
很好
Good. Good.
那么
Well,
所以说你没希望了 对吧?
basically you're fucked, aren't you?
# Don't buy me nothing for Christmas #
欢迎继续收看
Hi there, and welcome back.
还有三周就是圣诞节 你的竞争对手是Blue
So, Billy, three weeks till Christmas. Looks like the real competition is gonna be Blue.
他们上周上过节目 对我的歌大肆批评
Yeah. I saw them on the show last week. They weren't very nice about my record.
那群臭小子
No, little scamps.
不过他们是很有才华的歌手
But very, very talented musicians.
对 现在 你要为本节目赢家 提供奖品
Yeah. Uh, Billy, I understand you've got a prize for our competition winners.
是的 主持人
Yes, I have, Ant or Dec.
一支很好写的签字笔
It's a personalized felt-tip pen.
- 棒呆了 - 是啊
- Oh, great. - It's brilliant.
在玻璃上都能写字
It even writes on glass.
如果你有一张Blue的照片
So if you've got a framed picture like, for instance, this one of Blue,
就可以在上面写
you can just write on it.
# I won't ask for much this Christmas I won't even wish for snow #
# I'm just gonna keep on waiting #
# Underneath the mistletoe #
- 有很多小朋友在看 - 是喔
- Uh, a lot ofkids watching, Billy. - Oh, yeah.
小朋友们
Hiya, kids.
比利阿伯有件重要的事要说
Here's an important message from your Uncle Bill.
不要去买毒品
Don't buy drugs.
因为当偶像歌手就能免费嗑药
Become a pop star, and they give you them for free.
我们现在要进广告
And I do believe, uh, it's a commercial break, thank goodness.
待会见
We'll see you soon. Bye-bye.
圣诞节前三周
# Baby, all I want for Christmas is you #
圣诞节
啊我的天啊!
oh, look at him. Eew!
请等一下
Just a minute.
不要笑 这是艺术
Actually, they're not funny. They're art.
好吧 礼拜四 我家
Okay, let's say, uh, Thursday, my place? Great.
太好了 茱丽叶在另一线 她想请你帮个忙
But for now, I've gotJuliet on the other line. Can I patch you through? She wants to askyou a favor.
- 好 - 谢谢 对她好一点
- Okay, - fine. Thanks and, uh, be nice.
我一直对她很好 你明白我的意思友善点
I'm... I'm always nice. You know what I mean, Marky. Be friendly.
- 我总是 - 马克?
- I'm always... - Mark?
嗨 度蜜月愉快吗?
Hi. How was the honeymoon?
很愉快 多谢盛大的送别
Oh, it was great. And thanks for the gorgeous send-off.
- 我能帮什么忙吗？- 只是个小忙
- So, what can I do for you? - It's only a tiny favor.
我看过婚礼影片 糟透了
I've just tried the wedding video and it's a complete disaster.
- 根本没有拍起来 - 真糟糕
- It's come out all blue and wibbly. - Oh, I'm sorry.
我记得你也拍了不少 能借我看看吗？
And I remember you filming a lot in the day, and I just wondered if I could look at your stuff.
其实我并没有
Oh, no. Look, to be honest, I didn't really, you know... Please?
拜托啦 我只要一个我婚纱的画面
All I want is just one shot of me in a wedding dress that isn't bright turquoise.
我找找看 我记得洗掉了 别期望太高
Okay, I'll have a look, but to be honest, I'm pretty sure I wiped it.
我得走了
So don't get any hopes up. Must go.
你跟他有没有进展?
Any progress with our matchmaking plans?
没有 没希望了 我配不上他
No. I've done fuck all and never will because he's too good for me.
那倒是真的
How true.
别这样
Ouch. Stop.
你的手机又响了
And, of course, your mobile goes.
嗨 你好
Hello, hi. How are you doing?
圣诞派对安排得怎样？
So, how's the Christmas party going?
很好 我找到一个很棒的场地
Good. I think I've found a venue. Friend of mine works there.
- 什么地方？- 好
- What's it like? - Good, good.
是一间艺廊 有很多阴暗角落能做坏事
It's an art gallery. Full of dark corners for doing dark deeds.
是啊
Right. Good.
好 我看我应该先去看一看
Well, I suppose I should take a look at it or something.
你应该去的
You should.
Ah, bonjour, Eleonore. Bonjour, Monsieur Bennett.
欢迎回来 今年女朋友没来？
Welcome back. And this year you bring a lady guest?
没有 只有我一个人
Uh, no, there's a change of situation. It's just me.
我该为你难过吗?
Oh. Am I sad or not sad?
- 你应该早就猜到了 - 你要待到圣诞节吗？- 是的
- Well, I thinkyou're not surprised. - And you stay here till Christmas? - Yeah, yeah. Good.
很好 我找到了好清洁女工
Well, I find you a perfect lady to clean the house.
这是爱莉亚
This is Aurelia.
嗨
Ah.
Uh, bonjour, Aurelia.
Bonjour.
她不会说法语 跟你一样
Uh, unfortunately she cannot speak French, just like you.
- 她是葡萄牙人 - 哦
- She's Portuguese. - Ah, ah.
Bon giorno. Eusebio.
Uh, uh, molto bueno.
别再跟她鸡同鸭讲了
I think she's ten years too young to remember there was a footballer called Eusebio.
最后那一句是西班牙话
And the "molto bueno" is Spanish.
好 好 反正我很高兴认识你
Right, right. Uh, well, anyways, it's nice to meet you. And...
- 她下班请你送她回家好吗？- 没问题
- Perhaps you can drive her home at the end of her work. - Oh, absolutely.
"Con grande, uh, presoro."
你说啥？土耳其话吗?
Which is what? Turkish?
Bello.
Uh, bella.
Uh, montagna. "Arvarez."
好吧 沉默是金
No, right. Silence is golden.
颤音合唱团唱过这首歌
As the Tremeloes said.
唱得很棒
Clever guys.
不过原唱者是四季合唱团
Although I think the original version was by, uh, Frankie Valli and the Four Seasons.
他们很棒
Great... Great... Great band.
啊闭嘴啦
Oh, shut up.
总统先生
欢迎
Mr. President, welcome.
幸会了
It's a pleasure to meet you. Come on through.
请进 可惜尊夫人不能来
I'm sorry your wife couldn't make it, by the way. Oh, so is she.
是呀 不过她来了也没人陪
Although she would have been kind of lonely, I'm sure.
没错 真可悲 是吧
Yes. Pathetic, isn't it?
我一直找不到对象
Just, uh, never been able to tie a girl down.
可能政治是约会的致命伤
I'm not sure that politics and dating really go together.
是吗？我倒不觉得
Really? I've never found that.
那是因为你是大帅哥 我却像个欧巴桑
Well, difference is you're still sickeningly handsome, whereas I look increasingly like my Aunt Mildred.
- 我很嫉妒你的空军一号 - 谢谢 我们都爱它
- I'm very jealous of your plane, by the way. - Thank you. We love that thing, I'll tell you.
哈 娜塔莉
Ah, Natalie. Hi.
早安 你好吗？女士
Morning, ma'am. How's your day so far?
好极了
Excellent.
天呀 这个小妞真不错
My goodness, that's a pretty little son of a bitch right there.
你瞧见她的腿了吗?
Did you see those pipes?
是呀 她很棒 非常专业
Yeah, yeah. Oh, she's terrific... at her job.
绝对不行 我们不同意这点
No, absolutely not. We cannot and will not consult on that either.
- 这出乎意料 - 不应该是这样
- That is unexpected. - Well, it shouldn't be.
上一任政府说得很清楚
The last administration made it perfectly clear.
我们只是延用他们的政策
We're just being consistent with their policies.
恕我直言 这政策很烂
Well, with all respect, sir, they were bad policies.
谢谢你 亚历 这件事谈下去也不会有进展
Right, thanks, Alex. I don't think we're making progress here.
谈下一个议题 好吗
Let's, um, move on, shall we?
嗯 很有趣的一天
Well, now, that was, uh, an interesting day.
很抱歉我的立场强硬 但是我不想先随便答应你
Sorry if our line was firm, but there's no point in tiptoeing around today...
然后再让你失望四年
and then just disappointing you for four years.
我们有计划 我打算照计划进行
I mean, I have plans and I plan to see them through. Absolutely.
没问题 最后还有一件事
Now, there is one final thing I thinkwe should look at. It's very close to my heart.
我很关心 请等我一下
If you just give me a second.
你要什么我都给你
I'll give you anything you ask for,
只要不是我不想给的东西都行
as long as it's not something I don't wanna give.
嗨
Hi.
我逊毙了
Pathetic!
好醇的威士忌
It's great scotch.
我要
I'll, um...
我这就走了
I'll be going then.
嗨 娜塔莉
Uh, Natalie.
我们在为国家打拼的时候 我希望能再见到你
I hope to see much more of you as our two great countries work toward a better future.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
问吧 彼得
Uh, yes, Peter.
总统先生 这次来访愉快吗
Mr. President, uh, has it been a good visit?
非常令人满意
Very satisfactory indeed.
我们达到了目的
We, uh, got what we came for,
英美关系也跟以前一样特殊
and our special relationship is still very special.
首相呢?
And Prime Minister?
我喜欢关系 这个字眼 涵盖了各种罪恶
I love that word "relationship." Covers all manner of sins, doesn't it?
我恐怕它成了个坏关系
I fear that this has become a bad relationship.
美国总统想要什么就拿什么
A relationship based on the president taking exactly what he wants...
完全不理会对英国来说
and casually ignoring all those things... that really matter to, um,
很重要的事情
Britain.
英国虽不大 但也曾辉煌一时
We may be a small country, but we're a great one too.
我们有莎士比亚 邱吉尔 披头四 史恩康纳莱 哈利波特
The country of Shakespeare, Churchill, the Beatles, Sean Connery, Harry Potter,
贝克汉的黄金右脚
David Beckham's right foot.
贝克汉的黄金左脚
David Beckham's left foot, come to that.
欺负我们的朋友不算是朋友
And a friend who bullies us... is no longer a friend.
既然对方吃硬不吃软
And since bullies only respond to strength,
从现在起我也会更强势
from now onward I will be prepared to be much stronger.
请总统先生要有心理准备
And the president should be prepared for that.
总统先生 总统先生
Mr. President. Mr. President.
乔
Joe.
你妹妹在四线
It's your sister on line four.
好
All right.
我很忙 找我有什么事
Uh, yes, I'm very busy and important. How can I help you?
你发疯了吗
Have you gone completely insane?
- 我不能永远保持理智 - 你是首相必须保持理智
- Well, you can't be sensible all the time. - You can if you're prime minister.
- 财政大臣在另一线 - 才没有
- Oh, dear, it's the Chancellor of the Exchequer on the other line. - No, it isn't.
- 我再打给你 - 不 你不会打的
- I'll call you back. - No, you won't. You're...
当首相的老妹 私生活都变得透明了
The trouble with being the prime minister's sister is it does put your life into rather harsh perspective.
我老哥做了什么 他维护了国家尊严 我咧？
What did my brother do today? He stood up and fought for his country. And what did I do?
我做了一套龙虾装
# I made a papier-mache lobster head.
你在听什么？琼妮米雪儿
What is this we're listening to? Joni Mitchell.
你还在听琼妮米雪儿呀
I can't believe you still listen toJoni Mitchell.
我超爱她 真爱是永远的
I love her, and true love lasts a lifetime.
她教你冷漠妻子怎么去爱
Joni Mitchell is the woman who taught your cold English wife how to feel.
是吗？那我该写信去感谢她
Did she? Oh, well, that's good. I must write to her sometime and say thanks.
送哪个洋娃娃给黛丝的朋友？
Now, which doll shall we give Daisy's little friend Emily?
变装皇后还是皮鞭女王？
The one that looks like a transvestite or the one that looks like a dominatrix?
他燃起每个人的爱国之心
It's almost enough to make you feel patriotic.
这首歌献给超猛的首相大人
So here's one for our arse-kicking prime minister. I think he'll enjoy this.
献给黄金单身汉的老歌
A golden oldie for a golden oldie.
# Hold me #
# I'll give you all that you need #
# Wrap your love around me #
# You're so excited I can feel you getting hotter #
# Oh, baby #
# I'll take you down I'll take you down #
# Where no one's ever gone before And if you want more #
# lf you want more, more, more #
# Then jump for my love #
# Jump in and feel my touch #
# Jump If you wanna taste my kisses in the night #
# Then jump, jump for my love #
# I'll take you down I'll take you down #
# Where no one's ever gone... #
# Yeah. Um... Mary, I've been thinking.
玛丽 日本大使 改到明天四点好吗?
Can we move theJapanese ambassador to 4:00 tomorrow?
- 没问题 先生 - 很好 多谢了
- Certainly, sir. - Terrific. Thanks so much.
圣诞节前两周
你想吃？
Um, would you like the last, uh...
谢谢 不了
(Portuguese) Thank you very much but no.
你见过我老姐就知道原因了
If you saw my sister, you'd understand why.
那更好 我爱吃
That's all right, more for me.
别一直猛吃
Just don't go eating it all yourself,
你会吃成胖子的
you're getting chubbier every day.
我很幸运
I'm very lucky I've got a constitution...
我永远也吃不胖
where I never put on weight.
哦
Oh.
喂
Hello?
抱歉
Oop. Sorry.
喂？
Hello?
谢谢
Thank you. Ah, no!
噢 噢 噢 噢
Oh, no. Oh, no.
天呀 半本书泡汤了
Oh, God, it's half the book. Oh, no. Just... Just leave them!
别管它了 不重要啦 不值得你去捞
Please! They're not important! They're not worth it!
别去
Uh, stop. Stop.
反正都是垃圾
It's all just rubbish!
别管它了
Just leave it.
天呀 她跳下去了
Oh, God, she's in.
我不下去 她会觉得我很蠢
Right, and now she'll think I'm a total spaz if I don't go in too.
靠超冷的!
(Portuguese) Fuck it's cold.
靠冷毙了!
Fuck it's freezing. Fuck.
这本书最好很赞
(Portuguese) This stuff better be good.
不值得
It's not worth it,
这可不是莎士比亚
this isn't bloody Shakespeare.
我可不想为了一本
(Portuguese) I don't want to drown...
我姥姥都能写出的书而淹死
saving some shit my grandmother... could have written.
别捞了
Just stop. Stop.
猪头才会忘了影印副本
(Portuguese) What kind of idiot... doesn't make copies?
我应该影印副本的
I really must do copies.
不要有泥鳅
There'd better not be eels in here.
别踩到泥鳅
(Portuguese) Try not to disturb the eels.
天呀 那是什么
Oh, God! What the hell is that?
谢谢 非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you so much.
我要以你为一个角色命名
I know. I'll name one of the characters after you.
你也许该以我为一个角色命名
(Portuguese) Maybe you could name... one of the characters after me.
或是分给我百分之五十的版税
Or give me 50% of the profits.
或是分给你百分之五的版税
Or I could give you 5% of the profits.
这是什么小说?
(Portuguese) What kind of book is it?
嗯 嗯
Or, um...
爱情？
Or, um, uh, romance?
对 是
Ah-ah! Ah, yes, it's, um, uh...
推理 犯罪
Yes, uh, si, crime.
犯罪和谋杀
Crime. Uh, murder, you know.
可怕吗
Uh, scary? Uh, yes, sometimes scary.
恐怖吗?是的 有时会
And, uh, sometimes not.
有时不会 主要是写得烂得很可怕
Mainly scary how bad the writing is.
我该回去工作了
(Portuguese) I'd better get back to work.
你待会送我回家吗
Ah. (Portuguese) Later you'll drive me home?
当然了
Uh, sure, sure.
我最愉快的时刻
It's my favorite time of day...
就是送你回家
driving you.
我最悲伤的时刻 就是离开你
(Portuguese) It's the saddest part...
对不起
Oh.
接下来要介绍这位歌手
And coming up later this morning, it's this guy.
# 没有开始 没有结束 #
# There's no beginning There'll be no end #
# 因为在圣诞节… #
# Cos on Christmas... #
是阿公级的摇滚巨星 十点半 请别转台
The bad granddad of rock and roll here at 10:30. Do not switch off.
焦糖香蕉派？
Banoffee pie?
我不吃 谢谢
No, thanks. Thank God.
如果你要吃我会很伤心的
You would have broken my heart if you'd said yes.
是呀 算你走运
Oh, right. Well, lucky you.
我可以进去吗
Can I come in?
可以 我很忙
Uh, yeah, well, I'm a bit busy, but...
我只是顺路来看看录影带
Well, I was just passing and I thought we might check that video thing out.
我想用甜点跟你作交换 也许用巧克力？
I thought I might be able to swap it for some pie or maybe Munchies?
我真的不记得在哪儿了 我晚上再帮你找
Actually, I was being serious. I don't know where it is.
马克 我能说句话吗?
I'll have a poke around tonight... Mark, can I say something?
说吧
Yeah.
我知道你是彼得的死党
I know you're Peter's best friend.
而且
And...
我知道你从来都不太喜欢我
I know you've never particularly warmed to me.
别反驳
Look, don't... don't argue.
我们一直没机会做朋友 我希望能改变这一点
We've never got friendly, but I just wanted to say I hope that can change.
我这人真的很好 只是不会挑甜点
I'm nice. I really am, apart from my terrible taste in pie.
嗯
And...
我很想做你的朋友
it would be great if we could be friends.
没问题
Absolutely. Absolutely.
太好了
Great.
这并不代表能找到录影带
Doesn't mean we'll be able to find the video, though.
你第一次打来后我就找过
I had a real search when you first called and couldn't find any trace of it, so...
这个是彼得和茱丽叶的婚礼
Well, there's one here that says "Peter and Juliet's wedding."
是不是就是这卷？
Do you thinkwe might be on the right track? Oh, yeah, well...
是啊 哇 搞不好是哦
Wow. That... That could be it.
- 你不介意我？- 大概都洗掉了
- Do you mind if I just... - I've probably taped over it.
我录了"白宫风云"
Almost everything has episodes of West Wing on it now.
哦
Oh.
这就对了
Oh, bingo.
太好了
That's lovely.
你拍得真好
Well done, you.
好美哦
Oh, that's gorgeous.
谢谢你 这正是我所要的
Thank you so much, Mark. This is exactly what I was hoping for.
我看起来好美
I look quite pretty.
你都在拍特写
You've stayed rather close, haven't you?
全都是我的镜头
They're all of me.
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
是的
Yes.
可是
But...
你从来不理我
you never talk to me.
你只跟彼得讲话
You always talk to Peter.
你不喜欢我
You don't like me.
希望能用得上
I hope it's useful.
别放给别人看
Don't show it around too much.
要先剪接一下
It needs a bit of editing.
我得去吃午餐
Look, I've gotta get to a lunch.
早午餐
Early lunch.
你能自己出去吧
You can just show yourself out, can't you?
我一直很内向 你瞧
It's a... self-preservation thing, you see.
# Oh, I am what I am #
# I'll do what I want #
# But I can't hide #
# And I won't go #
# I won't sleep #
# And I can't breathe #
# Until you're resting here with me #
# And I won't leave #
# And I can't hide #
# I cannot breathe #
# Until you're resting here #
# And I won't go #
# And I won't sleep #
# And I can't breathe #
# Until you're resting here with me #
好
Yeah.
安妮 亲爱的 我的美人
Annie, my darling, my dream, my boat.
我要请你帮个忙
Uh, need you to do a favor for me.
没问题 为现时的大英雄做什么都行
Of course. Anything for the hero of the hour.
别问为什么 也别想得太多
Don't ask me why, and for heaven's sake, don't read stuff into this.
这是我个人的问题
It's just a weird personality thing.
可是 你知道娜塔莉吧
But, um, you know Natalie who works here?
- 那个胖妞？- 她算胖吗？
- The chubby girl? - Oooh, would we call her chubby?
她的屁股够大了 大腿也很粗
I think there's a pretty sizable arse there, yes, sir. Huge thighs.
嗯 随便啦
Yeah. Well, whatever. Um...
她人很好 可是我想请你
I'm sure she's a lovely girl, but I wonder if you could, um,
替她安排别的职务
redistribute her.
没问题
It's done.
山姆 睡不着吗
Hey, Sammo. Can't sleep?
我今天有个坏消息
I got some terrible news today.
- 说吧 - 琼安要回美国了
- Let's have it. - Joanna's going back to America.
- 你的女友是美国人？- 对 她是美国人
- Your girl's American? - Yes, she's American.
她不是我的女友
And she's not my girl.
她要回美国 我也不想活下去了
And she's going back to America. That's the end of my life as I know it.
这真是坏消息
That is bad news.
我们需要凯特
Well, we need kate and we need Leo,
也需要李奥 现在就需要他们
and we need them now.
来吧
Come on.
抓紧了
Hold on. Hold on.
闭上双眼
keep your eyes closed.
你相信我吗
Do you trust me?
我相信你
I trust you.
你相信我吗？我相信你
Do you trust me? I trust you.
- 猪头 - 滚开 别闹了
- Fool! - Get off, you big bully.
好了 睁开眼睛
All right. Open your eyes.
山姆 我相信她一定很特别
Well, you know, Sammy, I'm sure she's unique and extraordinary, but...
但是真爱并不一定只有一个
general wisdom is that, in the end, there isn't just one person for each of us.
凯特和李奥就是这样
There was for kate and Leo.
你也是这样
There was for you.
我也是这样 她是我的唯一
And there is for me. She's the one.
好吧 她叫琼安?
Fair enough. And her name's Joanna?
对 跟妈一个名字
Yeah, I know. Same as Mum.
噢
Yeah.
- 首相大人 - 谢谢你
- Prime Minister. - Thank you very much.
噢 抱歉
Oh, appolo... apologia. "Grandi..." Uh, grande familio.
这是圣诞礼物
Grande "predistione..." The Christmas presents. Stupido.
再见
Well, good-bye.
谢谢你
(Portuguese) Thank you.
这真
Um, it was, um...
我会想念你
(Portuguese) I will miss you.
你超慢的打字速度
And your very slow typing...
和你超烂的开车技术
and your very bad driving.
# 你知道我爱圣诞节 #
# You know, I love Christmas #
# 一直如此 #
# I always will #
# 我这种感觉 #
# My mind's made up #
# 不会改变 #
# The way that I feel #
# 没有原因 没有理由 #
# There's no beginning There'll be no end #
# 因为圣诞节 #
# 'Cause on Christmas #
# 可以依赖 #
# You can depend #
丹尼尔!
Daniel!
- 我想到办法了 - 谢天谢地 快说
- I have a plan. - Thank the Lord! Tell me.
女生都很爱摇滚歌手 对吧?
Well, girls love musicians, don't they? Uh-huh.
甚至怪胎都钓得到马子
Even the really weird ones get girlfriends. That's right.
至少成功干过一次
Meat Loaf definitely got laid at least once.
连林哥史塔都娶了庞德女郎
For God's sake, Ringo Starr married a Bond girl.
随便啦 学期末琼安要在演唱会献唱
Whatever. There's this big concert at the end of term, and Joanna's in it.
如果我参加乐团并且表现出色
And I thought maybe if I was in the band and played absolutely superbly...
她就可能会爱上我
there's a chance that she might actually fall in love with me.
- 怎么样？- 棒呆了 超正点
- What do you think? - I think it's brilliant.
只是有一个小小的问题
I think it's stellar, apart from the one obvious, tiny, little-baby, little hiccup.
- 我不会玩任何乐器？- 没错
- That I don't play a musical instrument? - Yes, sir.
这只是一个小问题
A tiny, insignificant detail.
生命之节奏
Too Lost In You
# 你看着我的眼睛 #
# You look into my eyes #
# 我离开我的心灵 #
# I go out of my mind #
# 我什么都看不到 #
# I can't see anything #
# 因为这爱的让我盲目 #
# Cos this love's got me blind #
# 让我难以控制 #
# I can't help myself #
# 我不能打破这个咒语 #
# I can't break this spell #
# 我甚至不能尝试 #
# I can't even try #
# 宝贝 我太痴迷于你 #
# Baby, I'm too lost in you #
# 被你套牢 #
# Caught in you #
# 迷失在关于你的每一件事 #
# Lost in everything about you #
# 是那么深 以致我不能入睡 #
# So deep I can't sleep, I can't... #
我最好去向员工敬酒
Anyway, I suppose I'd better go and do the duty round.
你真贴心
You're a saint.
# 你只是想让全世界看到 #
# And you just want the world to see #
我能跟老板跳舞吗?
Any chance of a dance with the boss?
好呀 没问题
Yeah, sure, sure.
只要你男友不介意
As long as your boyfriend doesn't mind.
# 它总能撕裂你的内心 #
# lt can tear you up inside #
他不是我男友
Not my boyfriend.
# 让你相信谎言 #
# Make your heart believe a lie #
# 更加坚强 骄傲而自豪 #
# lt's stronger than your pride #
# 爱的困扰是 #
# The trouble with love is #
# 无论你多快陷入 #
# lt doesn't care how fast you fall #
你今晚打扮得很美
You're looking very pretty tonight.
这是为了你
It's for you.
什么
Sorry?
这一切都是为了你 先生
It's all for you, sir.
# 但是我的世界已是深深的忧伤 #
# But now my world's a deeper blue #
# 我是如此悲伤 我也是一个聪明人 #
# I'm sadder, but I'm wiser too #
# 我发誓我不会再沉沦爱海 #
# I swore I'd never love again #
# 心灵的创伤永远无法愈合 #
# I swore my heart would never mend #
# 爱不值得如此伤痛 #
# Said love wasn't worth the pain #
你一定很兴奋 努力争取冠军宝座
This must be a very exciting moment for you, fighting for the Christmas number one.
- 情况如何？- 情况不妙
- How's it looking so far? - Very bad indeed.
Blue的销量比我多四倍
Blue are outselling me five to one,
不过我希望能迎头赶上
but I'm hoping for a late surge.
如果我得了冠军
And if I reach number one,
我答应在圣诞夜献唱
I promise to sing a song...
在电视上全裸
stark naked on TV on Christmas Eve.
- 你是说真的？- 当然了
- Do you mean that? - Well, of course I mean it, Michael.
想先睹为快吗 老色鬼?
Do you want a preview, you old flirt?
这样可得不到冠军
That'll never make number one.
我想他得跟每个人跳舞
I suppose it's his job to dance with everyone, isn't it?
跟某些人还要多跳
Some more than others.
跟我跳一支舞吧？机会难得
Just one dance... before we run out of chances.
你跟我？
Who, me?
- 你不想吗？- 不 我想啊
- Unless you, you just... - No, no.
谢谢
Good. Yes. Thanks.
# 让我相信你喜欢我 #
# Makes me trust you like I do #
# 深夜 我和你谈心 #
# Late at night, I talk to you #
# Hey, break us down #
# 犹如一朵鲜花 #
# Like a flower #
# 等待绽放 #
# Waiting to bloom #
# Like a lightbulb #
# 在漆黑的房间 #
# ln a dark room #
# 我只是坐在这 #
# I'm just sittin'here #
# 等你 #
# Waitin'for you #
# To come on home #
# And turn me on #
# Like the desert #
# Waiting for the rain #
# Like a school kid #
# Waiting for the spring #
# I'm just sittin'here #
# Waiting for you #
# To come on home #
# And turn me on #
# Turn me on #
我得走了
Well, I... I'd better go.
好吧
Okay.
晚安
Good night. Good night.
- 其实 我不必走 - 很好 - 我是说
- Actually, I don't have to go. - Right. Good. -I mean...
不 这样很好
No, no. That's... That's good. That's good.
就等我一下 好吗?
Just, um... Would you ex-excuse me for one second?
- 好 - 就一会儿
- Sure. - Just one... one second.
好 好了
Um, okay. That's done. Um...
请你十秒后再上楼
Why don't you come upstairs in about 10 seconds?
十秒?
Ten seconds? Ten seconds.
# For you #
# 会有不哭泣 #
# There'll be no crying #
# For you #
# 太阳会照耀 #
# The sun will be shining #
# 因为我觉得当我和你一起 #
# 'Cause I feel that when I'm with you #
# 什么都好了 #
# lt's all right #
扯下来
Just tug it. Okay.
# 我知道是对的 #
# I know it's right #
# 和鸣禽保持歌唱 #
# And the songbirds keep singing #
# 他们想知道评分 #
# Like they know the score #
# 我爱你 我爱你 我爱你 # - 你好美
- # And I love you I love you, I love you # - You're beautiful.
# 从未如此这样爱一个人 #
# Like never before #
我… 我最好去接一下
I'd... I'd better answer that.
哈啰 亲爱的
Hello? Hi. Hello, darling.
我没在忙 说吧
No, no, I'm not busy. No, fire away.
好
Right.
是的 我
Yes, I... I... I... I'm not quite sure...
我不敢保证今晚能不能 打电话找到教宗
it's gonna be possible to get the Pope on the phone tonight, but...
我肯定他很会躯鬼 可是
Yes. Yes, l-I'm... I'm sure... he's-he's very good at exorcism, but...
嗯 我肯定
Well, I'm I'm sure...
邦乔飞也是 我会去问的
Jon Bon Jovi is as well, and I'll definitely look into it.
好吗？好了 晚点再说吧
Okay? Okay, I'll I'll talk to you later.
好吧 拜了
All right. Bye-bye.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
没关系
No, it's... it's fine.
我弟弟 他病了 经常打来
It's my brother. He's... He's not well. He calls a lot.
- 很遗憾 - 不 没什么
- I'm sorry. - No, it's fine.
其实是这样的
It's fine. I mean, it's-it's not really... fine. It is what it is, and...
父母都不在了 我们都在这里 照顾他是我的责任
Sort of there being no parents now, and us being over here, it's my job to keep an eye on him.
不是责任 显然 我心甘情愿
I mean, not my job. Obviously I'm-I'm glad to do it.
没关系
That's okay.
我的意思是 人生充满突发和状况
I mean, life is full of interruptions and complications.
那么
So...
你能让他好一点吗
Will it make him better?
不能
No.
那也许
Then maybe...
不要接
don't answer?
你好吗?
Hey. How you doin'? Mm.
好
Right, right.
不 求求你 别这样 亲爱的
Oh, no. Oh, please. Oh, please. Please, please don't, little darling.
我俩会想出办法 不再让你痛苦了
L... Between the two of us, we'll find the answer, and it won't hurt anymore.
我不忙
No, no. No, I'm-I'm-I'm... I'm not busy.
当然 你要我过去我就过去
Of course, if you want me to come over, I will.
好吧
Mm-hmm. Okay.
今晚很尽兴 只是我好肥哦
That was a good night, except I felt fat.
- 别傻了 - 是真的
- Don't be ridiculous. - Oh, it's true.
我只穿得下
Nowadays, the only clothes I can get into...
帕华洛帝的衣服
were once owned by Pavarotti.
他穿的衣服很好看呀
I always think Pavarotti dresses very well.
蜜雅很漂亮
Mia's very pretty.
是吗
Is she?
你明明知道 亲爱的
You know she is, darling.
你要小心点
Be careful there.
你都有看电视吗
Have you been watching stuff on TV?
有
Yeah.
- 每晚都看 - 好呀
- Every night. - Oh, good.
每天都看
And every day.
- 护士想杀我 - 没有人想杀你 宝贝儿
- The nurses are trying to kill me. - Nobody's trying to kill you, babe.
谢谢
Thank you.
别这样 亲爱的
Don't do that, my darling.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不要这样
Don't do that.
我三点回来 买圣诞礼物真烦人
Right. Back at 3:00. Christmas shopping... never an easy or a pleasant task.
你要送我什么?
Are you gonna get me something?
嗯…
Uh...
不知道 还没想过 莎拉呢
I don't know. I hadn't thought. Where's Sarah, by the way?
她家里有事 不能来了
She couldn't make it in today. Family thing.
这只是宿醉的藉口
There's a word for "hangover" I've never heard before.
- 回头见 - 我很期待哦
- See you later. - Yes. Looking forward to it.
等不及了
A lot.
你要给我什么
So, are you gonna give me something?
昨晚我说得很明白
I thought I made it clear last night.
我什么都愿意给你
When it comes to me, you can have everything.
你需要什么
So, um, what do you need?
文具？钉书机？
Something along the stationery line? Are you short of staplers?
我不需要什么
No. I don't want something I need.
我想要美美的礼物
I want something I want. Something pretty.
好
Right.
好吧
对不起 我要送小柏去排演
Sorry I'm late. Had to drop off Bernie at rehearsal.
好 你去忙吧
Right. Well, listen, you keep yourself occupied for 10 minutes...
我去给妈妈买礼物
while I go and do the boring stuff for our mothers.
这个怎么样
How about this one?
让我想想 谢谢
Perhaps I'll think about it. Thank you.
你在找什么吗 先生
Looking for anything in particular, sir?
是的 那条项链多少钱
Yes, um... That necklace there. How much is it?
两百七十英镑
It's &270.
- 好 我要了 - 好极了
- Um, all right. Uh, I'll have it. - Lovely.
你要包装成 礼物吗
Would you like it... gift-wrapped?
- 好呀 - 太好了
- Uh, yes. All right. - Lovely.
让我放进盒子里
Let me just pop it in the box.
嗯
There.
请你快一点
Look, could we be quite quick?
没问题 我会快如闪电
Certainly, sir. Ready in the flashiest of flashes.
- 嗯 - 太好了 - 还没好
- There. - That's great. - Not quite finished.
我放口袋 不要袋子
Look, actually, l-I don't need a bag. I'll just put it in my pocket.
- 这不是袋子 先生 - 不是吗
- Oh, this isn't a bag, sir. - Really?
这不只是个袋子
This is so much more than a bag.
噢
Ooh!
请你快一点 好吗?
Could we be quite quick, please?
Prontissimo.
- 那是什么？- 肉桂棒 先生
- What's that? - It's a cinnamon stick, sir.
- 我不能等了 - 你不会后悔的 先生
- Actually, I really, uh, can't wait. - Oh, you won't regret it, sir.
你敢打赌？
Wanna bet?
再等一下就好
It's but the work of a moment.
就快好了
There we go. Almost finished.
还要泡优酪乳？
"Almost finished"? What else can there be?
沾满巧克力糖吗？
Are you gonna dip it in yogurt? Cover it with chocolate buttons?
不 先生 我要放进圣诞礼盒
Oh, no, sir. We're going to pop it in the Christmas box.
- 我不要圣诞礼盒 - 你要我包装成礼物呀
- But I don't want a Christmas box. - But you said you wanted it gift-wrapped.
- 没错 可是 - 这是最后的装饰
- I did, but... - This is the final flourish.
- 我能付钱吗？- 现在只要
- Can I just pay? - All we need now...
- 啊天呀 - 小枝冬青
- oh, God! - Is a sprig of holly.
- 不要 我不要 - 可是
- No. No. No. No. No bloody holly. - But, sir, the...
这样就好了
Leave it, leave it, just leave it. Ooh!
你在逛珠宝专柜？
Loitering around the jewelry section, I see. No.
- 没有 我只是随便看看 - 放心 我的期望并不高
- I was just looking around. - Don't worry. My expectations are not that high...
十三年来你只会送我丝巾
after thirteen years of Mr. "Oh, But You Always Love Scarves."
实际上 我是喜欢丝巾
Actually, I do love this one.
圣诞节前一周
你跑来干嘛?
Hey! What are you doing here?
为了买机票我把房子租出去了
Had to rent out my flat to pay for my ticket.
你不是真的要去吧?
You're not actually going ahead with this genuinely stupid plan?
当然是真的啰
Yeah, I bloody am.
你以为这是一袋衣物？
You think this backpack is full of clothes? Like hell it is.
里面装满了保险套
It is chockablock full of condoms.
太出色了 太出色了 真是完美 保持那个样子
Excellent, excellent. Perfect. keep that going.
看看
Look, um,
很抱歉有些冒失 但我想问…
sorry to be, uh, a bit forward and all that, but, uh,
你不想去喝杯圣诞酒 是吗？
you don't fancy going for a Christmas drink, do you?
我这么说 没什么其它的意思
I mean, nothing... you know, nothing implied at all.
只是或许可以去感受一下圣诞的气氛或是别的什么
Just, um, maybe sort of go and see something Christmas-y or-or-or-or something?
很明显 如果你不想去的话 你就没必要去了
Uh, obviously, if you don't want to, you don't have to.
我… 我现在是在瞎扯 抱歉
I was just, you know... I'm-I'm rambling now. Sorry.
不 那会很有趣的
No. That would be lovely.
哦 太好了
Oh! Great.
呀
Yea!
你知道 那真的太棒了
You know, that is really great.
通常我很害羞
Normally, I'm really shy about this sort of thing.
需要很长的时间才能鼓起勇气 所以 谢谢你
Takes me ages to get the courage up, so thank you.
林哥最棒
你为什么迟到？
Explain to me again why you're so late?
我不能也有秘密吗？
Can't a man have any secrets?
我们等了好长时间
We've been waiting for hours,
这是第一次预演
it's the first ever preview.
# Childhood dreaming is a thing of the past #
# Maybe you can bring us some hope this year #
# Visions of sugar plums have disappeared #
耶路撒冷的夜空繁星点点
"It was a starry night in ancientJerusalem...
小小耶稣在马槽诞生
and the babyJesus was in his manger."
伦敦市中心 语言学校
福尔摩斯不真的是个侦探
Sherlock Holmes is not a real detective.
这是到火车站的路吗？
(Russian) Is this the way to the train station?
我要半品脱的调酒
I would like half-pint of"churly."
我要一日游车票
I would like a one-day travel card.
天呀 我的肚子好痛
(Portuguese) Oh, my God, I've got a terrible stomachache.
一定是虾子不新鲜
It must have been the prawns.
米顿区有很多圆环
Milton Keynes has many roundabouts.
老天 这条鱼好大
(Portuguese) My goodness, this is a very big fish.
真好吃!
It tastes delicious.
# All alone on Christmas #
抱歉我这么爱发牢骚
Nobody ought to be alone on Christmas
# Tell me I've gotta know #
# Don't leave me alone #
你会全身受伤回来
You'll come back a broken man. Yeah.
是呀 炒饭炒到受伤
Back broken... from too much sex.
你这是自讨苦吃
You are on the road to disaster.
才怪 我要到美国找乐子
No. I am on shag highway, heading west.
我要出发了
Farewell failure.
美国辣妹 柯林来也
America, watch out! Here comes Colin Frissell...
# 他有根大老二 #
# And he's got a big knob #
密尔瓦基国际机场
- 载我到酒吧 - 什么样的酒吧？
- Take me to a bar. - What kind of bar?
任何酒吧 一般的美国酒吧
Just any bar. Just your average American bar.
- 你要喝什么？- 我要百威啤酒
- Can I help you? Yes. - I'd like a Budweiser, please.
啤酒之王
king ofbeers.
- 马上来 - 天啊
- One Bud coming up. - Oh, my God.
- 你是英国人吗？- 是的
- Are you from England? - Yes.
好可爱哦
Oh! That is so cute.
我是史黛丝
Hi, I'm Stacey.
珍妮？
Jeannie?
耶
Yeah?
- 这是 - 柯林
- This is... - Colin.
敝姓费
Frissell.
好可爱的名字
Cute name.
- 詹妮 - 他来自英国
- Jeannie. - He's from England.
是呀 巴西顿镇
Yep. Basildon.
噢 噢
Oh. Oh.
卡莉安会乐翻天
Wait till Carol-Anne gets here.
她超爱英国人
She's crazy about English guys.
哦 哦
Uh-huh.
- 姐妹们 - 快来见见柯林
- Hey, girls. - Carol-Anne, come meet Colin.
他来自英国
He's from England.
让开 女士们 这轮我请客
Well, step aside, ladies. This one's on me.
嗨 大帅哥
Hey, gorgeous.
超好笑的
That is so funny.
- 这叫什么？- 瓶子
- What-What do you call that? - Uh, bottle.
- 瓶子 - 这个咧？- 吸管
- Bottle. - What about this? - Uh, straw. Straw!
- 这个咧？- 桌子
What about this? Uh, table.
桌子 一样嘛
Table. Oh. It's the same.
- 你要住哪儿？- 不知道耶
- Where are you staying? - I don't actually know.
我想我要住汽车旅馆
I guess I'll just check into a motel, like they do in the movies.
哇塞 他超可爱的
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. That is so cute.
不行 听好 虽然我们才刚认识
No, no, no. Listen. This may be a bit pushy 'cause we just met you, but...
不过你不如到我们家住
why don't you come back and sleep at our place? Yeah. Yeah.
如果不太麻烦的话
Um, well, I mean, you know, if it's not too much of an inconvenience.
不会呀! 只有一个问题
Hell, no. But there's one problem.
- 什么？- 我们挺穷的
- What? - Well, we're not the richest of girls,
只有一张床 没有沙发
you know, so we just have... a little bed and no couch.
你得跟我们三个人一起睡
Oh. So... you'd have to share with all three of us.
天气这么冷
And on this cold, cold night,
- 人多 一挤会热得冒汗 - 对 没错
- it's... gonna be crowded and sweaty and stuff. - Yeah.
我们也买不起睡衣
And we can't even afford pajamas.
什么？
No?
所以嘛 我们会脱得光光的
Which means... we would be naked.
- 没问题 我觉得很不错 - 太好了
- No. No, I think it'll be fine. - Good. Great.
其实会更挤
The thing that's gonna make it more crowded...
你还没见过海莉呢
Harriet. You haven't met Harriet.
- 还有一个？- 放心 你会喜欢她的
- There's a fourth one? - Don't worry. You're totally gonna like her...
她是最性感的一个
cause she is the sexy one.
真的假的？
Really? Wow. Yeah. Yeah.
- 感谢上帝 - 他也是基督徒
- Praise the Lord. - And he's a Christian.
干杯
Cheers. Cheers.
# lf I could, then I would #
# I'll go wherever you will go #
# Way up high or down low #
# lf I could turn back time #
一晚只能拆一个 谁给爸爸买礼物了？
one present only each tonight. Who's got one for Dad? I have.
- 我买了 - 让妈妈先拆礼物 我去拿
- No, let Mummy go first. - I'll get it! I'll get it!
我要挑自己的 我要
No, no, no, no, no. I want to choose mine. I think I want...
- 这一个 - 照旧买了丝巾
- this one. - I have, of course bought the traditional scarf as well,
不过这份礼物比较特别
but this is my other... slightly special, personal one.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这倒是第一次
That's a real first.
- 用扯的 - 这是什么？
- Rip it. - What is it?
我要用 扯的?
I'm going to... All right, I'll rip it.
这真是令人意外
God, that's a surprise.
这是什么？
What is it?
是个CD 琼妮米雪儿的
It's a C.D. Joni Mitchell. Wow.
让你继续学会去爱
To continue your emotional education. Yes.
天呀 太好了
Goodness. That's great.
我亲爱的老婆大人
My brilliant wife. Ah. Yes.
我进去一下你不介意吧？
Actually, um, do you mind if I just absent myself for a second?
冰淇淋吃多了
All that ice cream. Uh...
亲爱的 让孩子们准备出门
Darling, could you just make sure the kids are ready to go?
我马上就来
I'll be back in a minute.
好 别着急
All right, take it easy.
- 我先来 - 我
- Mine first. - Mine.
# Moons and Junes #
# And Ferris wheels #
# The dizzy, dancing way that you feel #
# As every fairy tale comes real #
# I've looked at love that way #
# But now it's just another show #
# And you leave 'em laughin' when you go #
# And if you care #
# Don't let them know #
# Don't give yourself away #
# I've looked at love #
# From both sides now #
# From give and take #
# And still somehow #
# lt's love's illusions that I recall #
# I really don't know love #
# I really don't know love at all #
# Tears and fears and feeling proud #
# To say I love you right out loud #
# Dreams and schemes and circus crowds #
# I've looked at life that way #
- 噢 天啊
- # Oh, but now old friends # -oh my God!
- 真是奇迹 你们都穿好衣服了
- # They're acting strange # - It's a miracle! You're all dressed...
- 来 快 我们要迟到了
- Come on. We're horribly late! - # And they shake their heads #
快 上车 上车
# And they tell me that I've changed # out you go. Into the car, into the car.
# Well, something's lost #
# But something's gained #
# In living every day #
- 她注意到你没有？- 没有
- Has she noticed you yet? - No.
有情人要到最后才能成眷属
But you know the thing about romance is, people only get together right at the very end.
当然了
Of course.
我觉得好内疚 我从没关心过你的感情生活
By the way, I feel bad. I never askyou how your love life is going.
哇哦
No.
你也知道 我只爱你妈一人
As you know, that was a done deal long ago.
除非名模克劳蒂雪佛找我 那我就要你马上滚开
Unless, of course, Claudia Schiffer calls,
你这个没妈的杂种
in which case I want you out of the house straight away, you wee motherless mongrel.
我们要在每间房间里做爱 包括你的房间
Oh! No, no, we'll want to have sex in every room, including yours.
圣诞夜到处都在下雨
It's a rainy Christmas eve all over the Uk, and the big question is
今晚的单曲冠军究竟是谁？
"Who is number one on the Radio one Chart Show tonight?".
是Blue的新歌 还是麦比利的圣诞应景歌？
Is it Blue or the unexpected Christmas sensation from Billy Mack?
也许你们不相信
Well, you might have guessed it, although you may not believe it.
是麦比利
It's Billy Mack!
- 你是第一名 - 嗨 比利 嗨
- You are the champion! - Hi, Billy.
这是现场转播 你是第一名
Hello. We're live across the nation, and you're number one.
- 你要怎么庆祝？- 不晓得
- How will you be celebrating? - I don't know.
我可以像个落魄歌手
Uh, either I could behave like a real rock and roll loser...
跟我的胖经纪人喝个烂醉
and get drunk with my fat manager, or...
或是我放下电话
When I hang up I'll be flooded by invitations...
受到一大堆派对狂欢邀请
to a large number of glamorous parties.
希望是第二个选择 现在是麦比利的冠军单曲
Let's hope it's the latter. And here it is, number one from Billy Mack,
"圣诞节无处不在"
it's "Christmas is All Around."
天呀 别放这首烂歌啦
Oh, Jesus! Not that crap again!
# 我感觉它在我的手指… #
# I feel it in my fingers... #
比利 你的电话 宝贝儿
Bill. It's for you, babe.
艾尔顿 当然啰
Hello. Elton! Of-of course. Of-Of course.
只要派大礼车来我就去
Send an embarrassingly big car, and I'll be there.
今年的圣诞节会很棒
It's gonna be... a very good Christmas.
- 很好 - 我现在最好还是回去
- Right. - I'd better be getting inside, actually.
我妈妈还有… 你知道的
My mum and, you know... of course. Yeah.
当然 是 现在变得冷起来了
It's getting a bit cold.
嗯
Um...
- 好吧 晚安 - 晚安
- Well, good night. - Night.
嗯
Uh...
嗯 好吧
Uh, okay.
圣诞节我想要的… 就是你
All I want for Christmas... is you.
好
Right.
谢谢 晚安
Thank you. Good.
晚安
Good night.
呼
Ho.
# 我… 我做梦 #
# I'm... I'm dreaming #
# 梦想着一个白色的… #
# Dreaming of a white... #
大家瞧 是詹米舅舅 瞧 詹米舅舅来了!
oh, look, everyone! It's UncleJamie. # White Christmas #
太好了 见到大家真好
Yes. Oh, splendid. It's lovely... Iovely to see you all.
我要走了
And, uh, I'm off, actually.
可是 詹米 亲爱的
But, Jamie, darling.
抱歉
Sorry.
男人要去做男人该做的事
A man's gotta do what a man's gotta do.
詹米舅舅最讨厌
I hate UncleJamie.
- 我讨厌詹米舅舅 - 我讨厌詹米舅舅
- I hate UncleJamie. - I hate UncleJamie.
# 并试着听 #
# And try to listen #
# 听 #
# To hear #
# 所有的雪橇铃声 #
# All the sleigh bells #
# 在雪地里响起 #
# That are ringing in the snow #
盖特威机场请开快点
GatwickAirport, please. Fast as you can.
# 我想告诉你更多的时间我在想什么 #
# I wanna tell you one more time what I'm thinkin'about #
# 我… #
# I, I, I'm #
# 在梦想 #
# Dreaming #
# 一个白色的 #
# Of a white #
- 晚安 莎拉 - 晚安 卡尔
- Night, Sarah. - Night, karl. -# Christmas, yeah #
我
I, um...
# 每一个圣诞贺卡 #
# With every Christmas card #
- 圣诞快乐 - 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas.
# 那我写你 哦 #
# That I write you, oh #
# 我想让你知道 #
# I want you to know #
# 愿你天天 #
# May your days May your days #
# 那么快乐 #
# Be so merry #
# 快乐和阳光 #
# Merry and bright #
宝贝 你好吗？
Hi, babe. How's it going? Yeah.
你们在开狂欢派对吗？
Is it all party, party, party down there?
# 你所有的圣诞节 #
# All of your Christmases #
# 也许所有 可能所有 #
# And may all And may all #
# 你的圣诞节 #
# Of your Christmases #
# 宝贝 愿你所有的日子 #
# Baby, may your days #
# 愿你天天快乐 #
# May your days be merry, merry #
# 快乐和阳光 #
# So merry and bright #
山姆 吃饭了
Sam, time for dinner.
- 我说 我不饿 - 我烤了鸡肉串耶
- I'm not hungry. - Sam, I've done chicken kebabs.
请你看门上的标语
Look at the sign on the door.
(我说 我不饿)
# Your Christmases #
好
Right. # Be so bright #
太长了
It's a little long.
# 做梦 梦见一个白色 #
# Dreaming, dreaming of a white #
# 白色圣诞节 宝贝 #
# White Christmas, baby #
我去开门
I'll get it.
- 嗨 - 什么人？
- Oh, hi. - Who is it?
说是唱诗班的
It's carol singers.
唱诗班 赏他们小费 叫他们滚
Well, give 'em a quid and tell them to bugger off.
# 寂静的夜 #
# Silent night #
幸运的话 到了明年
# Holy night #
我会跟其中一个辣妹约会
# 一切是如此的平静 #
# All is calm #
# 整个世界都是明亮的 #
# All is bright #
# 照着圣母 #
# Round yon virgin #
现在我只想向你表白
我并没有任何期望
# Mother and child #
# 神圣的婴儿 #
# Holy infant #
但是今天是圣诞夜
# 那么温柔 温和 #
# So tender and mild #
圣诞夜一定要说实话
# 睡在天上 #
# Sleep in heavenly #
对我来说 你很完美
# 平静 #
# Peace #
# 无比安详的睡着 #
# Sleep in heavenly peace #
我将爱你到永远
# 寂静的夜 #
# Silent night #
直到你变成这样
# 圣夜 #
# Holy night #
# 牧羊人 #
# Shepherds quake #
# 看见 # 圣诞快乐
# At the sight # Merry Christmas.
# 辉煌流 #
# Glories stream #
# 从天上远处 #
# From heaven afar #
# 日月星辰 #
# Heavenly hosts #
# 唱哈利路亚 #
# Sing alleluia #
# 基督救世主 #
# Christ the Savior #
# 出生 #
# Is born #
# 基督救世主诞生了 #
# Christ the Savior is born #
够了
Enough.
这就够了
Enough now.
你在这儿干嘛？你应该在艾尔顿强那儿
What the hell are you doing here? I mean, you're supposed to be at Elton John's.
我才去了一两分钟
Yeah, well, I was there for a minute or two,
就有一个领悟
and then... and then I had an epiphany.
- 真的？- 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
来 上来吧
Well, come on. Just come up.
你有什么领悟？
So, um, what was this epiphany?
跟圣诞节有关 你发现圣诞节无处不在?
Um, it was about Christmas. You realized it was all around?
不是 圣诞节要跟你爱的人
No. I realized that Christmas is the time...
在一起度过
to be with the people you love.
- 没错
- Right. - And...
人生苦短 稍纵即逝
I realized that as dire chance and-and fateful cock-up would have it,
我来了
here I am...
我都活到五十多岁
mid-fifties...
到现在才发现我的大半辈子
and without knowing it, I've gone and spent most of my adult life...
都跟胖经纪人在一起
with a chubby employee.
虽然我很不想这么说
And much as it grieves me to say it,
但是我在世上唯一爱的人
it-it might be that the people I love...
其实是你
is, in fact, you.
- 这太令人意外了 - 是啊
- Well, this is a surprise. - Yeah.
你一去找艾尔顿强就变成同志了?
Ten minutes at Elton John's, you're as gay as a maypole.
我是认真的
No, look, I'm serious here.
我离开了艾尔顿强那儿
I left Elton's, where there were a hefty number...
放弃了一脱拉库的半裸辣妹 上床嘿咻的大好机会
of half-naked chicks with their mouths open... in order to hang out with you...
在圣诞夜
at Christmas.
- 哇喔 - 这是个错误 胖子
- Well, Bill... - It's a terrible, terrible mistake, Chubs.
不过我发现你才是我最亲的人
But you turn out to be the fucking love of my life.
老实说 虽然我老是抱怨
And to be honest, despite all my... complaining,
我们却一起度过了美好的人生
we have had a wonderful life.
嗯 谢谢你
Well, Thank you.
我是说 这是我的荣幸
I mean, yeah, come on. It's been an honor.
我感到骄傲
I feel very proud.
别犯傻啦
Oh, don't-don't be a moron.
来吧 一起灌酒看A片吧
Come on. Let's get pissed and watch porn.
亲爱的先生 亲爱的大卫
Dear sir. Dear David.
圣诞快乐 新年如意
Merry Christmas, and I hope you have a very happy New Year.
我要为那件事道歉
I'm very sorry about the thing that happened.
我觉得好尴尬 也觉得好蠢
It was a very odd moment, and I feel like a prize idiot.
特别是因为 圣诞节不说 何时能说？
Particularly because, if you can't say it at Christmas, when can you, eh?
我是你的
I'm actually yours, with love.
爱你的娜塔莉
Your Natalie.
我是你的 爱你的娜塔莉
I'm actually yours. With love, your Natalie.
杰克 我要用车
Jack, yeah, I need a car. Right now.
马上要 谢谢
Thank you.
不用等我回来
Oh, don't wait up.
- 旺斯沃斯 比较穷的那一区 - 好的 先生
- I'd like to go to Wandsworth. The dodgy end. - Very good, sir.
# 你的眼睛告诉我你是怎么想我的 #
# Your eyes tell me how you want me #
# 我能感觉到你心跳 #
# I can feel it in your heartbeat #
# 我知道你喜欢你所看到的 #
# I know you like what you see #
哈利街 门牌几号？
Harris Street. What number, sir? Oh, God.
天呀 这是世上最长的一条街 我不知道门牌号码
It's the longest street in the world, and I have absolutely no idea.
# 让你的爱缠绕在我周围 #
# Wrap your love around me #
# 你是如此的兴奋 我能感觉到你越来越热 #
# You're so exciting I can feel you getting hotter #
- 娜塔莉住这儿吗？- 没有
- Hello. Does Natalie live here? - No.
- 谢谢你 抱歉打扰了 - 嗯 嗯
- Right. Fine. Thank you. Sorry to disturb. - Eh... Uh...
你不是首相吗？
Aren't you the prime minister?
是的 圣诞快乐
Uh, yes, in fact, I am. Merry Christmas.
赶在除夕前拜访每一家人
Oh! Part of the service now. I'm trying to get round everyone by New Year's eve.
娜塔莉住这儿吗？
Ah! Hello. Uh, does Natalie live here?
- 没有 - 好吧
- No, she doesn't. - Oh, dear. Okay.
你是来唱圣诞歌吗?
Are you singing carols?
- 不是 - 拜托 你唱啦 拜托
- Uh, no. No, I'm not. - Please, sir. Please. Please.
- 嗯 我想我可以唱 - 拜托啦
- Well, I mean, I suppose I could. - Please.
好吧
All right.
# 好国王温撤拉斯 #
# Good king Wenceslas looked out #
# 看着史蒂芬的庆典 #
# on the Feast of Stephen #
# 到处都在飘大雪 #
# When the snow lay round about #
# 雪花纷飞晶莹剔透 #
# Deep and crisp and even #
# 那晚月光格外明亮 #
# Brightly shone the moon that night #
抱歉 娜塔莉住这儿吗？
Hello. Sorry to disturb. Does Natalie live here?
不 她住在隔壁
No. She lives next door.
太好了
Ah. Brilliant.
你不是我认为的那个人吧？
You're not who I think you are, are you?
我是的 抱歉打扰了
Yes, I'm afraid I am, and I'm sorry about all the cock-ups. Not my fault.
我的内阁超逊 希望明年会好些
My cabinet are absolute crap. We hope to do better next year.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas to you.
娜塔莉在吗？
Ah. Hello. Is, uh, Natalie in?
靠我的大衣在哪里？
Where the fuck is my fucking coat?
- 喂 - 喂
- Oh. Hello. - Hello.
这是我爸妈 我舅舅东尼 舅妈葛琳
Um, this is my mum and my dad... and my Uncle Tony and my Auntie Glynne.
- 喂 - 幸会了
- Very nice to meet you. - And, um,
这位是首相
this is the prime minister.
我们看得出来啦
Yes, we can see that, darling.
我们要迟到了
And, um, unfortunately, we're very late.
- 学校要举行圣诞表演 大卫 - 哈
- It's the school Christmas concert, you see, David. - Ah.
学区小学都参加了 连私立学校都
It is the first time all the local schools have joined together. Even St Basil's.
- 你话太多了 妈妈 - 你有什么贵干 先生？
- Too much detail, Mum. - Uh, anyway, how can we help, sir?
我只需要娜塔莉
Well, I... just needed Natalie.
处理一些国事
On some state business.
是哦 当然了
Oh. Right. Yes. Of course. Right.
那你就待会再来吧 胖子 娜塔莉
Well, perhaps you should, uh, come on later, Plumpy. Uh, Natalie.
我不想耽误你们的时间
Well, listen, I don't want to make you late for the concert.
- 不 这没什么 - 小奇会很失望
- No, it's nothing really. - keith'll be very disappointed.
- 没什么 这并不重要 - 我花了几个月才缝好章鱼装
- No, really, it doesn't matter. - The octopus costume's taken me months.
八支脚很难缝耶
Eight is a lot of legs, David.
嗯 嗯
Hmm. Um...
我载你们去
Listen, why don't I, um, give you a lift,
我们可以在车上谈这件国事
and then we can talk about this... state business business in the car.
- 好 - 太好了
- Okay. - Lovely.
谢谢你
Lovely. Yes.
大家坐好了
Hold tight, everybody.
- 学校有多远？- 转个弯就到
- How far is this place? - Just around the corner.
好 嗯
Ah, right. Well, uh,
我只想说
I just wanted to say, um,
谢谢你送的圣诞卡
Thank you for the Christmas card.
不客气 那天的事很抱歉
You're welcome. Look, I'm so sorry about that day.
我一进去他就走过来 壁炉正旺
I mean, I came into the room and he slinked towards me and there was a fire,
他是美国总统
and he's the president of the United States, and...
我保证 我们什么也没发生
Nothing happened. I promise.
我只觉得好蠢
And I just felt like such a fool because...
实际上我满脑子都在想你
I think about you all the time, actually.
- 你才是我真正 - 我们到了
And I thinkyou're the man that I really... We're here.
爱的人
Iove.
真的很近
Oh, wow. That really was just round the corner. Uh...
嗯
Um...
哇
ow!
(叹息)
(Sighs)
听好 我…
Well, look, I, uh...
你知道 我最好不要进去
I think I'd better not come in, you know?
别让政客抢走孩子们的风头
Last thing anyone wants is some sleazy politician stealing the kids' thunder.
请你进去 一定会很棒
No, please come. It'll be great.
不了 最好不要
No, I... I'd better not.
不过我也不想
But I... will be very... sorry...
离开你
to drive away from you.
等我一下
Just give me one second.
不可思议 你们两个在哪约会？
John's been very mysterious. Where did you two meet?
嗯 嗯 嗯 嗯
Um... Um... Um... Um...
马赛机场
进来吧 我们到后台看
Come on in. We can watch from backstage.
好吧 泰利 我不会太久的
Okay. Uh, Terry, I won't be long.
这一定要保密 好吗？
But look. This, um... This has to be a very secret visit, okay?
这是我的母校 我很熟 来吧
Don't worry, This was my school. I know my way around. Come on.
羊咩咩都好了 你还没有
Look, look, the sheep are ready already, and you're not even...
哇 大卫
oh, David! Ah! Ah!
你好吗？嗨 大家好
Oh, how are you? Hi, guys. Hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey.
你没事吧？你怎么会跑来?
You all right? What the hell are you doing here?
你知道 我每次都告诉你的秘书
Well, you know, I... I always tell your secretary's secretary's secretary...
这儿有什么活动 没想到你真的会来
that these things are going on, but it never occurred to me you'd actually turn up.
我早该来了
Well, I thought it was about time l-I did.
我只想保密 所以我要躲起来偷偷看
I just didn't want anyone to see, so I'm gonna hide myself somewhere and watch the show. Good luck.
祝好运 黛丝 祝好运 小柏
Good luck, Daisy. Good luck, Bernie.
我见到老哥真的好高兴哦
I have to tell you, I've never been gladder to see my stupid big brother.
- 谢谢你 - 不客气
- Thank you. - It's all right.
你还没介绍呢
Oh, now. We haven't been introduced.
对 嗯
Oh, right. Um...
- 这是盖文 - 你好 盖文
- Well, this is Gavin. - Oh, hello, Gavin.
我的贴身保镳 这是娜塔莉 我的
Sorry. My copper. And this is Natalie, who's my, um...
我的外烩主管
who's my uh... uh... catering manager.
哦
Oh. Hi.
小心他的咸猪手哦
Catering manager. Watch that he keeps his hands off you.
二十年前他就喜欢你这类型
Twenty years ago, you'd have been just his type.
我会很小心 今天是平安夜 别乱来
I'll be very careful. Don't try something, sir, just because it's Christmas.
我是说真的
No, seriously.
开始啰 快点
Oh, come on. Showtime. Quickly.
- 回头见 好吗？- 也许吧
- Um, look, see you after, yeah? - Yeah, probably. Yeah.
- 谢谢你 首相大人 - 不用客气
- Thank you, Prime Minister. - It's all right.
快
Come on. Right.
# 抓住流星 放进口袋 #
# Catch a falling star and put it in your pocket #
# 留着下雨天用 #
# Save it for a rainy day #
# 抓住流星 放进口袋 #
# Catch a falling star and put it in your pocket #
# 别让它偷偷溜掉 #
# Never let it fade away #
希勒小学要表演一首圣诞歌曲
Hillier School would now like to present their chosen Christmas number.
主唱是十岁的琼安同学
Lead vocals by 10-year-old Joanna Anderson.
合音由她母亲指挥
Backing vocals coordinated by her mother,
伟大的珍安德森女士
the great Mrs. Jean Anderson.
有些教职员决定参与合唱
Um, some of the staff have decided to help out, and, uh,
为此 请原谅我们
for this, we askyou to forgive us.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
# 圣诞节我要的不多 #
# I don't want a lot for Christmas #
# 我只要一样东西 #
# There's just one thing I need #
# 我并不在乎 #
# I don't care about the presents #
# 圣诞树下的礼物 #
# Underneath the Christmas tree #
# 我只要你属于我 #
# I just want you for my own #
# 因为我深爱着你 #
# More than you could ever know #
# 请让我愿望成真 #
# Make my wish come true #
# 今年圣诞节 #
# All I want for Christmas #
# 我只要你 #
# Is you #
# 圣诞节我要的不多 #
# I don't want a lot for Christmas #
# 我只要一样东西 #
# There's just one thing I need #
# 我并不在乎 #
# I don't care about the presents #
# 圣诞树下的礼物 #
# Underneath the Christmas tree #
# 我只要你属于我 #
# I just want you for my own #
# 因为我深爱着你 #
# More than you could ever know #
# 请让我愿望成真 #
# Make my wish come true #
# 今年圣诞节 我只要你 #
# All I want for Christmas is you #
# 你 宝贝儿 #
# You, baby, oh #
# 灯光在闪烁 四处亮晶晶 #
# All the lights are shining so brightly everywhere #
# 孩子的笑声充满空间 #
# And the sound of children's laughter fills the air #
# 笑声充满空间 #
# Laughter fills the air #
# 人人都在欢唱 #
# Everyone is singin' oh, yeah # # oh, yeah #
# 我听见雪橇的铃声 #
# I hear those sleigh bells ringin'#
# 圣诞老人 你不把我需要的人带给我吗？#
# Santa, won't you bring me my honey #
# 你不把我的宝贝带给我吗？#
# Won't you please bring my baby to me #
# 圣诞节我不需要很多 #
# I don't want a lot for Christmas #
- # 我只需要 # - # 我只需要 #
- # This is all I'm asking for # - # All I'm asking for #
# 我只想看到我的宝贝儿 #
# I just wanna see my baby #
# 就站在我的门前 #
# Standing right outside my door #
# 我只要你属于我 #
# I just want you for my own #
- # 因为我深深着你 # - # 深爱着你 #
- # More than you could ever know # - # You will ever know #
# 让我的愿望实现 #
# Make my wish come true #
# 今年圣诞节我只要 #
# All I want for Christmas #
# 你一个 #
# Is you #
# 今年圣诞节我只要 #
# All I want for Christmas #
# 你呀 你 #
# And you, and you #
# 你呀 你呀 #
# 今年圣诞节我只要你一个 #
# All I want for Christmas #
圣诞节快乐
惨了
Right.
这儿并没有那么隐密 怎么办？
So, not quite as secret as we'd hoped. What do we do now?
微笑 鞠躬
Smile. Little bow.
挥手
And a wave. Thank you.
哇 是首相
Wow! The prime minister!
根本没有想到 我是说 你想像得出吗？
Absolutely no idea. I mean, can you imagine?
我们一会见 好吗？我们再谈 再见
I'll see you later, all right? I'll speak to you.
换作是你 你会怎么做？
Tell me, if you were in my position, what would you do?
什么意思？
What position is that?
老公买了一条金项链
Lmagine your husband bought a gold necklace...
却在圣诞节送给别人
and, come Christmas, gave it to somebody else.
你会先沉住气
Oh, Karen. Would you wait around to find out if it...
- 晚安 - 晚安 圣诞快乐
- Good night. - Night, night, darling. Happy Christmas.
先沉住气看看是否只是礼物
Would you wait around to find out if it's just a necklace...
或者是一夜情和项链
or if it's sex and a necklace or if, worst of all,
或是最糟糕 是爱和项链？
it's a necklace and love?
换作是你 你会留下来吗？
Would you stay knowing life would always be a little bit worse?
- 还是放弃一切逃跑？- 呀 天啊
- Or would you cut and run? - Oh, God.
我错了
I am so in the wrong.
我是个大傻瓜
A classic fool.
没错 你也把我当傻瓜
Yes, but you've also made a fool out of me.
你也否定了我的人生
You've made the life I lead foolish too.
孩子们
Darling. Whoo! Darlings!
你们演得好棒哦
Oh, you were wonderful!
我的小龙虾 你真的
My little lobster, you were so...
怎么说？
What is that word?
棒呆了
Orange.
回家吃点心吧 爸爸马上就来
Come on. I've got treats at home. Dad's coming.
山姆
Sammy!
太棒了 你打得真好 孩子
Fantastic show! Classic drumming, son.
谢了 不过计划失败了
Thanks. Plan didn't work, though.
- 跟她说 - 说什么？
- Well, tell her then. Tell her what?
- 跟她说你爱她 - 不行 他们今晚就要走
- Tell her that you love her. - No way. Anyway, they fly tonight.
那更好
Even better. Sam,
你不跟她表白会后悔一辈子的
you've got nothing to lose, and you'll always regret it if you don't.
我应该多跟你妈说的
I never told your mum enough.
我应该每天都跟她说我爱她 因为她每天都很完美
I should have told her every day because she was perfect every day.
你也看过电影 不到最后一刻不能落幕
You've seen the films, kiddo. It ain't over till it's over.
好 爸爸
Okay, Dad.
就这么办吧 我要为爱撞得头破血流
Let's do it. Let's go get the shit kicked out of us by love.
- 等我一下 - 好？
- Yes! Just give me one sec. - Yeah.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry. Sorry.
没关系 是我的错
That's... okay. My fault.
不 这不是你的错
No, no, no. Really, it wasn't.
你是山姆的爸爸 对吧？
You're Sam's dad, aren't you?
对 其实是继父
Yeah. Stepdad, actually.
- 我是丹尼尔 - 我是卡莉 卡莉
- Daniel. - I'm Carol. Carol.
- 好 我回来了 走吧 - 好 嗯
- Okay, I'm back. Let's go. - Yeah.
希望能再见面 凯伦
Well, I hope we'll meet again, Karen.
卡莉
Carol.
- 我们一定会的 - 好
- I'll make sure we do. - Yeah? Good.
- 跟她说 - 说什么？
- Tell her. - What?
- 你知道嘛 - 别闹了
- You know... - Don't be such an arse.
- 她在那里 - 哪里？
- Look. There she is. - Where?
那里
Over there.
啊糟了
Oh, no.
没关系 我们赶去机场我知道个近路
It's okay. We'll go to the airport. I know a shortcut.
晚安
我是来请你
(Portuguese) Good evening.
让我和令嫒结婚
Senhor Barros? Sim.I am here to ask your daughter... for her hands in marriage.
你要娶我女儿？
You want to marry my daughter?
对
Yes.
快过来 有人在这儿
Come here, there is a man at the door.
他要跟你结婚
He wants to marry you.
- 我没见过这个人 - 管它呢？
- But I've never seen him before. - Who cares?
你要把我卖给陌生人？
You're going to sell me to a complete stranger?
谁说我要卖给他？
Sell? Who said sell?
我还要给他钱呢
I'll pay him.
对不起 是另一位千金爱莉亚
Pardon me. I'm meaning...your other daughter Aurelia.
她不在这 她在工作 我带你去
She's not here she's at work. I'll take you.
- 你给我乖乖待在家 - 我才不会啦
- You. Stay here. - As if I would.
猪头
Stupid.
老爸要把爱莉亚卖给他当奴隶
Father is about to sell Aurelia...
等等
Wait, wait!
往纽约VS003班机的旅客请登机
糟了
Oh, no.
你最好别答应他 爸爸
You better not say yes, Father.
闭嘴 2003年小胖妹
Shut up, Miss Dunkin' Donut 2003.
- 我们不是乘客 - 你们不能进去
Look, we're not actually flying, but... You can't come through without a boarding pass.
这孩子只想跟他的真爱道别
Not even to let the boy say good-bye to the love of his life?
不行
No.
- 对不起 山姆 - 登机证 先生
- Uh, I'm sorry, Sam. - Boarding pass, sir?
等一下 我有 请帮我拿一下
Now, just a moment. I know I've got it here somewhere. Would you mind hanging on to that?
- 除非 - 怎样？
- Unless... - What? What?
- 你想冲进去吗？- 拿着这个
- Do you want to make a run for it? - Hold on to that as well.
- 我应该吗？- 是的
- Do you think I should? - Yeah.
好吧 好耶
Okay. Yes!
我一定是在喝咖啡时弄掉了
No, I must have left them where I was having a cup of coffee. I'm sorry.
显然他想杀死爱莉亚
Apparently he is going to kill Aurelia.
酷哟
Cool.
琼安
Joanna.
山姆？
Sam?
- 我以为你不知道我的名字 - 我当然知道
- I thought you didn't know my name. - Of course I do.
天呀 我得走了
Oh Jesus. Here. I've gotta run.
- 爱莉亚呢？- 我为何要告诉你?
(Portuguese) - Where is Aurelia? - Why should I tell you?
这个人要跟她结婚
This man wants to marry her.
不行 她是我最好的服务生
He can't do that she's our best waitress.
晚上好
Boa noite, Aurelia.
Boa noite, Jamie.
美丽的爱莉亚
Beautiful Aurelia...
我是来请你
I've come here with a view to asking you...
嫁给我
to marriage me.
我知道你一定觉得我疯了
I know I seems an insane person... because I hardly knows you...
不过有时候 爱情是没有道理的
but sometimes things are so transparency,
不需要任何理由
they don't need evidential proof.
我可以住在这儿 你也可以到英国定居
And I will inhabit here,or you can inhabit with me in England.
当然要去英国啰
Definitely go for England, girl.
你会遇见威廉王子 然后嫁给他
You'll meet Prince William... then you can marry him instead.
嘘
Shh!
我当然不期望你跟我一样疯狂
Of course I don't expecting you...to be as foolish as me,
我也猜到你会拒绝我
and of course I prediction you say no...
不过今晚是圣诞夜我只想试试
but it's Christmas and I just wanted to...check.
天呀 快答应他呀 瘦妹
Oh, God say yes, you skinny moron.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这会很好
That will be nice.
我会说好的
"Yes" is being my answer.
太容易了
Easy question.
你说什么？
(Portuguese) What did you say?
我答应他
Yes, of course.
太好了
Bravo!
你学了英语？
You learned English?
以防万一
Just in cases.
一个月后
# 我可能不会永远爱你 #
# I may not always love you #
# 但只要你上方有星星 #
# But long as there are stars above you #
- 黛丝哈啰 - 这是葛妲
- Hello, Daisy. - This one's Greta.
你好 葛妲
Hello, Greta.
她来了 这是爱莉亚
Well, here she is. This is Aurelia.
这是茱丽叶 这是彼得
This is Juliet. This is Peter. Hi.
- 马克 我没看到你 - 我只是顺便跟来
- Mark. Hi. Didn't see you. - Yeah, just thought I'd tag along.
詹米的朋友都好帅哦
Jamie's friends are so good looking.
他都没跟我说过
He never tells me this.
也许我挑错老公了
I think maybe now I have made the wrong choice?
- 挑错了英国佬 - 她的英文不太好
Picked the wrong Englishman. She can't speak English properly. She doesn't know what she's saying.
爸爸
Dad! Dad!
- 天啊
- # So what good would living do me # - oh, God!
- 你有买礼物吗?- 当然有
- Did you get us any presents? - As a matter of fact I did.
谢了 老爸
Thanks, Dad.
- 你好吗？- 我很好
- How are you? - I'm fine. I'm fine.
你回来就好
Good to have you back.
来 回家吧
Come on. Home.
她来了
There she is.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hello.
- 他应该亲她 - 不 这样就很好
- Oh! He should have kissed her. - No, that's cool.
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
嘿 你们两个在这儿干嘛啊?
Hey, what are you two doing here?
- 也许我最后可以跟她上床 - 下流
- Might get a shag at last. - Naughty.
- 得走了 - 再见
- Uh, gotta go. - Bye.
哇
Whoo-hoo!
# 世界可以显示与我无关 #
# The world could show nothing to me #
这是海莉
Now, this... is Harriet.
见到你真高兴
Hi. Really pleased to meet ya.
你好 海莉 希望你不介意 我带我姐妹一起来了
Hello, Harriet. I hope you don't mind. I sort of brought my sister to stay.
这是卡莉
This is Carla.
她人很好
She's real friendly.
你好 你一定是东尼
Hello. You must be Tony.
我听说你超帅
I heard you were gorgeous.
- 天呀 你好重哦 - 闭嘴啦
- God, you weigh a lot. - Oh, shut your face.
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 # # 只有上帝知道 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you # # God only knows #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 # # 只有上帝知道 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you # # God only knows #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 # # 只有上帝知道 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you # # God only knows #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 # # 只有上帝知道 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you # # God only knows #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 # # 只有上帝知道 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you # # God only knows #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 # # 只有上帝知道 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you # # God only knows #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 # # 只有上帝知道 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you # # God only knows #
# 只有上帝知道我没有你 #
# God only knows what I'd be without you #
# 只有上帝知道我 #
# God only knows what I'd be #
# 爱的烦恼 #
# The Trouble With Love Is #
# 爱也许是由许多神奇的东西组合而成 #
# Love can be of many splendored thing #
# 不能否认它能带来的快乐 #
# Can't deny thejoy it brings #
# 成打的玫瑰花 钻戒 #
# A dozen roses, diamond rings #
# 梦想和童话故事 #
# Dreams for sale and fairy tales #
# 它使你听到一首交响曲 #
# lt'll make you hear a symphony #
# 你想要看清这个世界 #
# And you just want the world to see #
# 但是爱如药片使你盲目 #
# But like a drug that makes you blind #
# 每次总是愚弄你 #
# lt'll fool ya every time #
# 爱的困扰是 #
# The trouble with love is #
# 它总能撕裂你的内心 #
# lt can tear you up inside #
# 让你相信谎言 #
# Make your heart believe a lie #
# 更加坚强 骄傲而自豪 #
# lt's stronger than your pride #
# 爱的困扰是 #
# The trouble with love is #
# 无论你多快陷入 #
# lt doesn't care how fast you fall #
# 你都不能拒绝呼唤 #
# And you can't refuse the call #
# 总是让你唯唯诺诺 #
# See, you got no say at all #
# 喔 #
# Oh #
# 现在我已经历过它的真实 #
# Now, I was once a fool, it's true #
# 我遵循规则玩着爱的游戏 #
# I played the game by all the rules #
# 但是我的世界已是深深的忧伤 #
# But now my world's a deeper blue #
# 我是如此悲伤 我也是一个聪明人 #
# I'm sadder, but I'm wiser too #
# 我发誓我不会再沉沦爱海 #
# I swore I'd never love again #
# 心灵的创伤永远无法愈合 #
# I swore my heart would never mend #
# 爱不值得如此伤痛 #
# Said love wasn't worth the pain #
# 尽管我仍然听到它在呼唤我的名字 #
# But then I hear it call my name #
# 爱的困扰是 #
# The trouble with love is #
# 它总能撕裂你的内心 #
# lt can tear you up inside #
# 让你相信谎言 #
# Make your heart believe a lie #
# 更加坚强 骄傲而自豪 #
# lt's stronger than your pride #
# 爱的困扰是 #
# The trouble with love is #
# 无论你多快陷入 #
# lt doesn't care how fast you fall #
# 你都不能拒绝呼唤 #
# And you can't refuse the call #
# 总是让你唯唯诺诺 #
# See, you got no say at all #
# 每次我转身 #
# Every time I turn around #
# 我想我都已明了 #
# I think I've got it all figured out #
# 我的心一直在呼唤 #
# My heart keeps callin' and I keep on fallin'#
# 我一次又一次的陷入 #
# Over and over again #
# 悲伤的故事总是重复发生 #
# The sad story always ends the same #
# 站在滂泼大雨中 #
# Me standin'in the pourin'rain #
# 似乎无论我做什么 #
# lt seems no matter what I do #
# 我心似裂成两瓣 # # 爱情的烦恼就是这样 #
# lt tears my heart in two # # The trouble with love is #
# 爱情的烦恼 #
# The trouble with love #
# 耶 # # 它总能撕裂你的内心 #
# Yeah # # lt can tear you up inside #
# 它总能撕裂你的内心 # # 让你相信谎言 #
# lt can tear you up inside # # Make your heart believe a lie #
# 让你相信谎言 #
# Make your heart believe a lie #
# 更加坚强 骄傲而自豪 #
# lt's stronger than your pride #
# 爱的困扰是 # # 它可以深入你的灵魂 #
# The trouble with love is # # lt's in your heart It's in your soul #
# 你不会得到任何控制 #
# You won't get no control #
# 你都不能拒绝呼唤 #
# And you can't refuse the call #
# 总是让你唯唯诺诺 #
# See, you got no say at all #
# 爱的烦恼就是这样 # # 喔 耶 #
# The trouble with love is # # Oh, yeah #